The idea for Sharp ratio is
to consider our return, or
our rewards in the context of risk.
As we mentioned before,
most finance folks consider risk to
be standard deviation or volatility.
We're looking for
a measure that essentially
adjusts a return for that risk.
So, here are a couple of examples
that I want you to think about,
and we'll have a little
quiz associated with it.
But we have three example charts here,
where we're comparing two
stocks against one another.
So in this first one we've got ABC and
XYZ and both of them have about
the same volatility, except one returns
a little bit more than the other.
In this next question,
question two, they both return
exactly the same amount.
But one of them is more
volatile than the other.
And finally,
we have again these two stocks.
One, ABC, returns 11%, XYZ returns 9%,
but ABC is much more volatile than XYZ.
So I want you to think about this and
mark which portfolio or
stock you think is better in
each one of these examples.