For number one here,
ABC is the correct answer because
its volatility is the same but
its total return is higher,
so all else being equal,
higher return is better.
In this next one,
the correct answer is XYZ.
And the reason is, XYZ had the same
return as ABC, but it was less volatile.
So, all else being equal,
less volatility is better.
Now, number three was a trick question.
[LAUGH] ABC has higher return, but
it's offset by a higher volatility.
XYZ has lower return, but
that's offset by lower volatility.
So, you don't really have enough
information to make the choice here.
You can sort of stand back and
squint and look at it, and
tell you what your gut says, but we
need a qualitative way to measure this.
That's what the Sharpe
ratio is all about.