This is the best answer, here's why.
First of all, observe that
we're dividing by volatility
here on the bottom.
So as things become more volatile,
the ratio goes down.
We've got return on
portfolio here on the top.
So as return goes up,
the metric goes up.
And finally,
we subtract the risk free return here.
So as risk free return increases,
the value of our metric decreases.
Meaning, essentially we need to have
a higher return on our portfolio.
Than the risk free metric in order
to have a positive number here.
This is indeed the form
of the sharp ratio.
There are a few more details.
But this is essentially the ratio
devised by William Sharpe