The correct answer is 12.7.
That's a really,
eye-watering Sharpe ratio.
Anyway, these numbers are just
made up for example, so
it's not surprising we might
get an absurd number here.
But, here's how we calculate that.
Remember our Sharpe ratio
is the square root of 252
because that's how frequently
we are sampling the data, daily.
252 days in a year, square root of 252.
A lot of people probably saw
this 60 days of data and
thought that it should
be square root of 60.
It's not correct.
It's the frequency that you're sampling.
Anyways, getting back to it, it's square
root of 252 times the mean of portfolio
return minus risk free return divided by
standard deviation of our daily return.
So that becomes square root of 252 times
10 bips minus 2 bips divided by 10 bips.
This just becomes 0.8, and
multiply it all out, and you get 12.7.