Our objective in this class is to get
you up and running quickly, to show you
some real data, and some code you can
use to view it and manipulate it.
And just give you a feeling
that you know what's going on.
So we're going to take you
from examples of raw data
all the way to visualization.
Now let's get started with the data.
In this class we're going to
work almost entirely with
data that comes from CSV files.
CSV files are plain text.
The C stands for comma, S stands for
separated, V is values.
So comma-separated values.
Let me show you an example of
what might be in a CSV file.
Most CVS files start with a header line.
In this example,
this is a CSV file that's telling
us about weather conditions.
So we've got temperature,
pressure and humidity and
that tells us what information is
in the columns that are to follow.
Following our header line we
have lines or rows of data.
So these numbers here make up our data.
Again, header row and
rows of data, where each data
element is separated by a comma.
Now the files that we're going to be
working with, the stock data files,
have thousands of lines and
many more columns as well.
Our objective for this lesson is to
show you how to read in data like this,
focus, say, on one column or another,
and create a plot from that data.
Okay, so
now you've seen an example with weather.
Let's start thinking about stocks.