Okay.
So, let's take a look at some real
stock data.
We provide for
you in this class hundreds of CSV files
that represent the prices
of stocks over time.
Here's an example from one of
those files that you provided.
This is data from the file HCP.csv.
So, here is our header row and
here is the information that
you'll find in one of these files.
So, Date,
which date is the information for?
Open, this is the price
that the stock opened at.
In other words, in the morning,
when trading on the exchange began,
that was the first price of the day for
that stock.
High, throughout the day,
what was the very high price,
what was the very low price, and
at which price did the stock close?
So when we reached 4 o'clock,
what was the final price?
Volume, that's how many shares of
the stock traded altogether on that day.
And finally, this value, adjusted close,
which is a little bit
different from close.
And this is something we cover in the
next course where we talk about finance.
I'll talk about it a little bit here,
as well.
But let me delay talking about it for
a moment.
Okay.
I fleshed out this data a little bit.
First thing I want you to notice is that
the dates start with most recent dates,
and then as you go forward into
the file, you find older dates.
So, what that means, more or
less, is that we sort of go backwards
through time in these files.
Now, this is a feature, if you will,
of data from Yahoo, and that's where
we got our data for this class.
Thanks very much, Yahoo.
And this is just what a real
one of those files look like.
Now later when we read the data in,
we managed to get it in the right order,
and Dave will tell you
a little bit more about that.
Now, I had talked a little bit earlier
about Adjusted Close and Close.
Let me tell you a bit more
about what that means.
Now Close in this data
is the actual price
that was reported at the exchange
when the stock closed for that day.
Adjusted Close is a number that
the data provider generates for us.
And it's adjusted,
as the name implies, for
certain things like stocks,
splits, and dividend payments.
Now, on the current day, let's pretend
for the moment that we're in 2012,
adjusted close and
close are always the same.
However, as we go back in time,
we eventually see that adjusted
close and close differ.
So if we go all the way
back to the year 2000,
we'll note that the actual price
the stock closed at was $25,
but this adjusted price was only $5.36.
Now, what you can observe from
that is as we go forward in time,
if we had purchased this
stock back in 2000 and
held it to 2012,
what are we looking at there?
About eight or
nine time return over those
12 years, so 800 to 900% return.
If you looked only at just
the actual price on the market,
it's only a factor of about two, but
this adjusted close reflects things like
I said, like dividend payments,
and splits, and so on.
So that's what is in
an actual stock CSV file.
And this is the data that we're going to
be working with throughout this course
and the next two parts of the course.