We're going to make heavy use
of a library called Pandas.
This library was created by
Wes McKinney at a hedge fund call AQR.
It's used at many hedge funds and
by many people in the finance industry.
One of the key components of Pandas
is something called the dataframe.
And I'm going to show you a little
bit about what that looks like.
So this is the basic
layout of a dataframe.
We have our symbols along the top, so
our columns represent
symbols in the stock market.
Like, SPY which is an ETF
representing the S&P 500,
AAPL the symbol for Apple,
GOOG for Google, GLD for Gold.
And the rows are the dates over time, so
we go back as far as 2000,
then come all the way up to 2015.
So again, symbols from left to right,
one column for each symbol,
and time coming down like this.
So here's our dataframe fleshed
out with a little bit of data.
I made up some of these numbers,
so it's not intended to be
gospel truth, but notice how we have,
let's say this is closing prices.
So we see these numbers for
SPY, Apple, Google, and GLD.
Now, there are some special or
unusual values here.
NaN, that stands for
not a number, and that's
Python's way of saying hey, I don't
know, I don't have information for this.
The reason you see those values here is,
back in 2000, Google
did not exist as a publicly traded
company, and neither did the ETF GLD.
Now these NaN values can cause problems,
and
we'll be talking about
those in a later session.
Now as I said,
this might represent closing prices, but
Pandas can also handle additional data
in a sort of three dimensional sense.
So you can have a dataframe that
represents, again in columns,
our particular symbols,
and in rows, dates.
This one can be close,
we can have another one that has, for
the same stocks and the same dates,
volume on those dates, and
adjusted close, and so on.
So Pandas is a very flexible way to
read in, manipulate, and plot data.
Now I've shown you,
kind of at a high level,
what this data looks like and
what Pandas looks like.
I'm going to hand it over to Dave now,
and
she's going to show you some
real live examples with Pandas.
She's going to show you how to read
this data in, and plot it and so on.
So here's over to you, Dave.