Pandas provide a number of
functions that makes it easy
to read in data like the .csv
file we just had a look at.
Here's a code that reads in
AAPL.csv into a data frame.
So, first of all we will have
to import the pandas library.
To avoid writing pandas every time
we use a functionality of it,
we rename it as PD.
So, this is the main function,
which will call the test run function.
Let's have a look what's there in it.
Pd.read_csv, as the name suggests,
will read AAPL.csv into a data frame,
which we name it as df.
As of now, imagine dataframe as
a structure similar to the 2D arracy.
That is, with rows and columns.
Let's go ahead and print this.
So here's the entire csv
file on your console.
As you can see, the entire data
is loaded in your console, but
just to have an idea of the .csv file,
you can just print the top
five rows of the data frame.
This is how you do it.
Data frame dot head.
Dot head is the functionality provided
by the pandas for the data frame
that would help you to view just
the top five lines of the .csv.
That will give you a rough idea of
what the .csv actually contains.
Let's go ahead and print this.
So here it is.
Just the top five lines
of your data frame.
You can observe that all the columns
of the .csv can be viewed here.
You will also observe there is
a column that is not named and
has values 0, 1, 2, 3.
And this is not from the .csv.
These are called index for the data
frame, which help you to access rows.
Similarly, you can view last
five values using the df.tail.