Now let's do some more
processing on the data frame.
We can start with finding
the maximum closing value for
each of the stock AAPL and IBM.
So here's the code.
The test_run function simply loops
over two symbols, AAPL and IBM,
and will print the maximum closing
value of each of the stock.
Let's call the function
get_max_close along with the symbol.
Here's the function that will
compute the maximum closing value.
Let's see what get_max_close
function does.
The first step would be to read
in the csv into the data frame.
The next step would be to get only
the closing values from the entire
data frame, which means we have
to extract the column close.
This is how you do it.
df[, pass the parameter of
the column name, that is, 'Close'.
Make sure you include
the inverted commas.
The last step is to calculate
the maximum value, and
it is as simple as calling the .max()
function over the extracted data.
Let's go ahead and print this.
Here is your output.
The max close for the AAPL is 680.44 and
the max close for the IBM is 209.5.