Now let's do some plotting.
It's easy to plot data
in the data frame.
Here's how you plot
Apple's adjusted close.
First let's call a library
that would help us to do this.
We import a library name, matplotlib.
Do not worry about the details.
You will learn them eventually
in the further lessons.
But to plot the adjusting close,
we first need the adjusting
close data from the data frame.
And, as you learned in
the previous video,
we can slice over the column
using the square brackets.
Plotting the adjusting close is as
simple as calling a plot function.
To show the plot on your screen, we need
to add one more line and this plot.show.
Now let's run this code.
Here's your first graph.
You can observe there is no x-axis
label, no y-axis label, no header also
the data is printed in reverse order
since the CSV is in the reverse order.
So the Apple prices are not moving down,
they are just printed inversely.
In the coming lessons,
you will learn how to fix it.
As of now,
enjoy the power of the Python Pandas
that can plot information
using just one line of code.
Get ready to plot some data by yourself.
I'll be back with a quiz.