Okay, let's step through
these one by one.
A, Train several parameterized
polynomials of differing degree.
Yes, we could use that to
create an ensemble, but
that's not the best answer.
B, Train several KNN models
using different subsets of data.
Yes, that's good too, but
it's not yet the best answer.
C, Train several KNN models
with randomized Y values.
This is, of course, a terrible idea and
would give you mush.
D, Combine A and
B into a super ensemble.
Yes, that is the best answer.
E, combine B and C.
And of course, that is mush as well and
we're not going to do it.
Okay, we're actually going to look now
at this method of creating an ensemble
of learners, training several KNN
models using different subsets of data.