Now as you know,
we want to use reinforcement
learning algorithms to trade with.
So let's think now about how we can map
the trading problem to reinforcement
learning.
Okay, so consider each of these factors.
Buy, sell, holding long, Bollinger
value, return from trade, daily return.
And then consider,
is that item a description of our state
that we ought to consider
before we make a trade?
Is it an action that we give to
the market to cause a trade to occur?
Or is it a potential reward that we
would use to inform our algorithm for
learning how to trade.
And it's potentially the case that some
of these may serve more than one role.