Okay, let's step through
these one at a time.
Buy and sell are actions.
So, those are directives
we give to the market or
the environment to change it,
and potentially change our state.
Holding long is a part of the state,
it tells us whether we
are holding the stock or not.
We might also be holding short
if we had shorted of the stock.
So holding long is a part of the state.
Bollinger value,
that's a feature, a factor
that we can measure about a stock,
and that's part of the state as well.
That would inform us whether we wanted
to act on it in some way with an action.
Return from trade,
when we finally exit a position.
That is our reward.
We might lose money, so it would be
a negative reward if we lost money.
We might make money and that'd be
a positive reward, so that's R a reward.
Daily return,
that could be either a state,
in other words a factor we consider for
deciding what to do,
but it could also be a reward,
we'll get into that more later and
you'll see how it could be one or
the other.