So there are actually
several that satisfy that.
Infinite horizon is a little bit iffy
because the robot can go this way and
get a dollar on every other move and
that will add up to infinity.
It can go here and get the $1 million
and then come back and do that and
it will add up to infinity.
So it's possible that infinite
horizon will cause it to do that but
there's two equivalent solutions.
Finite with n=4,
no it won't get to that $1 million.
Because if it tries to go that way,
it'll only get negative reward here, but
it'll get positive reward
if it goes that way.
However, if we let n go out to 10,
boom, it'll reach that $1 million.
And finally, discounted reward, where
each dollar in the future is only worth
0.95, and that gets smaller as we get
further and further into the future.
Still, by the time we get to the eight
steps that it takes to reach this
reward It's still so huge that that's
clearly the optimal thing to do.
Okay, so
those are the answers to which horizons
will cause us to get to that $1 million.