I'd like you to consider
these three portfolios.
Now, each of the green dots represents
an asset that's in the portfolio.
And it's on this risk
versus reward scatter plot.
We've indicated the weights of
the assets by the size of the dots.
So for instance, this portfolio has most
of its assets in these two equities,
whereas this one has most of
its assets in these three.
Now, over here in this right column,
I indicate with a big orange circle
the risk/return level for
several different portfolios,
and what I want you to do is match these
resulting portfolios to these weights.
So, give it a go and I'll come back and
show you the answer.