There's one last topic I wanted to
talk about with regard to portfolio
optimizers and modern portfolio theory.
Consider these assets, and
also recognize that for
any particular return level,
there is an optimal portfolio.
So let's suppose we picked
this return level, and
that this is the optimal portfolio.
In other words, this portfolio reflects
weightings of all these assets
that provides the lowest risk for
this particular return.
Now, we can compute this for
all the potential returns
from the minimum return stock
here up to the maximum.
And if we did that for all of them, in
fact there's an infinite number of them,
so we couldn't really do it for
all of them.
You get a line.
So our maximum return
portfolio is up here and
it would consist entirely
of that one asset.
But as we bring the return down we
find a number of other portfolios
all the way down to here.
A couple of different things to
observe that are interesting.
One is as you reduce the return
sometimes this curve comes back
in this direction,
indicating that actually the risk is
increasing as we reduce the return.
So for the most part, people don't
want those sorts of portfolios.
In other words, who wants a lower
returning portfolio with more risk.
So we typically look only at
portfolios above this line.
As you might have guessed, the name of
this line is the efficient frontier.
So what does that mean,
the efficient frontier?
It means that there are essentially
no portfolios out here.
And that any portfolio that's
on this side of the frontier,
it's suboptimal in some way.
So for instance,
if you had a portfolio here,
you are assuming this much risk, for
a lower return than you could have, than
if you were up here on the frontier.
Or if you were targeting
this much return,
you could be over here
with regard to risk.
So any portfolio inside here is not
efficient because it's either higher
risk or lower return than it could be
if we were on the efficient frontier.
One last thing to mention about
the efficient frontier is if you draw
a tangent line from the origin
to the frontier where it
hits is the max sharp ratio
portfolio for all of these assets.
In practice the efficient
frontier isn't used for
that much other than as a theoretical
device, but people do often like to plot
the efficient frontier so they can see
where there portfolio is In relation to
the assets that they're using and where
they could be in terms of efficiency.
Okay, that is all.
I will see you online soon.
Thank you very much.