Most of these are hard.
This one's hard.
This one's hard, and this one,
and let me explain why.
This one is hard because of
this flat area here and here.
Suppose the minimizer tested this point
here and then tried on either side.
It wouldn't be able to find
any gradient to follow, so,
it wouldn't know which direction to go.
This one is difficult for
at least two reasons.
One is it has several local minima that
aren't necessarily the global minima.
So, it might iterate and
find, say, this as a minima.
But notice that actually there's this
other two that are actually smaller.
And then if these two have
exactly the same value,
turns out we have two global minima.
So, those sorts of conditions are tough
for these minimizers to solve.
This one is challenging A,
because of this flat area, but
also because of this discontinuity.
So, four examples, three of them would
be hard for our minimizer to solve.
Now, I'm not saying that these
are not solvable by optimizers.
In fact, there are optimizers that
can solve these problems with
varying degrees of success.
And they're likely to find a minima,
just not guaranteed to find the minima.