Our first step in considering data is
to think about how it's aggregated.
In other words, imagine that many,
many trades are happening
on different exchanges.
How is all that data combined and
how is is reported back to us so
that we can analyze it and use it.
The finest resolution of
data is called a tick.
A tick represents a successful by cell
match or a successful transaction.
So let's suppose that this time
there's a successful transaction $100
was the price and 200 was the volume.
So we record that here
with a single point.
A little bit later there was another
transaction 9905, a 100 shares.
Now, something to keep in mind is
each of these transactions happens at
no specific time.
It happens only when the buy and
sell are matched.
So there's no guarantee
that there's going to be
a trade in any particular minute or
any particular hour.
It just happens when it happens.
Each exchange provides its own data
feed regarding these transactions.
So you can subscribe to these feeds and
see at each tick when a transaction
happens on any particular exchange.
So I've added some red
dots here that represent
transactions that might be
happening on another exchange.
Note that the prices
are a little bit different,
the volumes of course
might be different.
All of this happening simultaneously and
the prices of different exchanges aren't
guaranteed to be exactly the same.
Now for highly liquid stocks,
there may be hundreds or
thousands or hundreds of thousands of
transactions like these every second.
Collecting and using all these ticks for
all the exchanges over a long period of
time would result in a lot of data,
and it becomes very complex.
Tick data is usually consolidated into
minute by minute or hour by hour chunks.
So I've drawn some boundaries here.
Let's suppose those
are minute boundaries, and
we collect all the data together
within each minute, and
represent it as open, high,
low, close and volume.
So the open is the first
transaction within the time period.
So we came in here,
we had a transaction at 100, so
our open value is 100
within this time period.
High, well you look at
the entire time period and
you see what was the highest price.
The highest price here was also 100.
Low was 99.05, close is the last
transaction and that was 95.50.
And volume is just the total
volume during that time period.
So it's 200 plus 100 plus 300,
so 600 shares.
So for this minute of time
we've consolidated all that
information into open, high,
low, close, and volume.
Similarly we go to the next minute and
consolidate it in the same way.
So in this next minute our open was 99,
our close 99.95,
low is 99, high was 99.95 and
our volume was 300.
And we will continue throughout
the day to consolidate the data at
each minute like this.
And depending on your data feed,
this might be the result say,
for one exchange or it might be
combined across multiple exchanges.
In this course,
these time boundaries are in days.
So the data we'll be
working with is daily data.
And so we'll be looking at what is the
data at the end of the day for each day.
Now, all of the concepts
that we teach here,
you can just as easily apply
at smaller time periods.
It just requires more computing,
faster computing, more and
larger databases, and so on.
So that's why we look at
daily data in this course,
is there's a little bit
less data to work with.
It's easier for you to download and
work with and so on.