So, let's start over here,
going back from today,
our adjusted price is
the same as the price today.
So, as we go back and we get to this day
where there is a $100 in the actual.
There's no change, it's still
a $100 also for the adjusted okay,
we go back further on this day of the
split, again, no change that would have
been $50, but we're looking to
calculate the price just before $100.
In other words, when the actual price
was 100 just before that split,
what would the adjusted close be?
Well, we divide everything by 2
remember, so we would have 50 here.
So it would cruise along like this.
And again, here we divide by two because
that's what our recent split was and
we would have 25 here.
So this correctly
represents that if you.
If you bought the stock on this day
it would double in value by
the time you got to this day.
And if you bought it on this day and
held it all the way to here, you would
actually get four times your value.