So here I've redrawn that same scenario.
We've got the price of a stock,
trundling along.
On this date, the dividend is announced
that it will be paid on this date.
And so we see, in general,
the price rising up until that date and
then a strong drop.
And again, the consensus value for
the company is about $100.
Let's consider now how we might adjust
historical prices for this situation.
Again, adjusted price as of today or
the latest day in our data,
is always the same as the actual price.
And as we go back in time,
it remains about the same
until we hit one of these events
like a dividend or a split.
So we treat, historically, the price in
the same way that we do with this split.
In other words,
just before the dividend is paid,
we adjust all of these prices down
by the proportion of the dividend.
So in this case we adjust
everything down by about 1%,
all the way back in history.
So our adjusted price
continues like this.
Now to double check this for
rationality,
consider that you bought
the stock around this date and
you held it all the way
though the dividend payment
you would get an increase in value
of your holding of about one dollar.
So the adjustment is
achieving its purpose,
which is to allow us to not worry
about dividends and splits.
Just go back in time, buy,
and hold the share, and
see how much our value accumulates.
So for the data we'll be working
with in this class, which are daily
close values, we have in our
data both actual and adjusted.
And in almost every instance I
will assume that we're using
adjusted closed prices
in our calculations.
Another couple things to reiterate about
adjustments is the last day in our file,
usually that's as of today, the adjusted
and actual close value are the same.
So any day that you look,
say you've gotta go to Yahoo Finance or
Google Finance and
you get adjusted close and
actual close, you'll see that today
they're exactly the same price, but
as you go back in time they
will begin to diverge and
the prices we use are adjusted for
both dividends and
splits, and it's very important
that you always use adjusted close.
One other thing to mention is
suppose we had this data as of 2012.
And so this last date here in our file
is some date in 2012, and you go and
you look at the adjusted close,
let's suppose this is some date in 2010.
That value, that adjusted close value,
will be different if you
gather data from, say, 2015.
So if you go to Yahoo and
get today's adjusted close,
there will certainly, for
most stocks, there will be dividends and
splits that have occurred since 2012.
And so this adjusted close
price today in Yahoo's data,
will be different, most likely
lower than the adjusted close for
that date,
if you had gathered it in 2012.
I know it's a little bit tricky,
the key point is for
projects in this class you need to use
the data that's provided for the class.
It was gathered as of 2012.
If you go to yahoo and get new data,
you're going to get different answers
for the projects, so
just keep that in mind.