One of the things we do in this
class is to simulate strategies that
we might develop.
We roll back time, and pretend that we
traded on certain dates according to
certain signals, and we see what the
result of our strategy might have been.
Now to do that, you have to start
with some universal stocks.
One of the most common
universes is the S&P 500.
When you simulate your trading,
you roll back time and
you look at that universe of stocks.
You apply your algorithm to choose
which stocks you might buy.
A very common mistake that people make
is that they look at the membership
of that universe, as of today.
Then they go back in time and they use
that list of stocks for their strategy.
So let's suppose we go back in time,
we take the current list of the S&P 500,
and we run our strategy and
our strategy is just doing great.
I'm going to call that
the biased strategy.
So why is it biased?
Well, we're selecting from stocks
way back here that we knew
were existing over here,
so there's a built in bias
that these stocks are going to do well
because they weathered the storm here.
Now consider, what if we use
the S&P 500 as it was back in 2007?
So a lot of the stocks from
back then did just fine,
they survived, but a lot didn't.
68 stocks from the S&P 500 died.
They completely went away,
from 2007 to 2009.
So if you applied the same strategy
that appears to be so awesome,
but you use the real members
of the S&P 500 from back then,
you're probably going to have
a significantly lower performance.
And the difference between
these two is the bias.
The lesson learned is to use
survivor bias free data and
that's available from
a number of providers.
It's not usually free, but it's not
necessarily that expensive either.
But if you do that, you'll avoid
this sort of false optimism for
a strategy that you develop.
Okay, that's it for dealing with data.
I hope you found the lesson useful and
we'll see you again soon.
Bye-bye.