Let's consider now what
happens to the model
that comes out when we
change the value of k.
So we've got three k nearest
neighbor models here.
Each one is using
a different value of k, and
I want you to match the value
of k to the output model here.
Okay, so I want you to look
at these different charts.
Each one of these models shown in
red is using a different value of k.
So I want you to fill
in these little boxes,
which chart corresponds
to the value of k.
So one of these charts
was created with k=1,
one was created with k=3, and
another was created with k=N,
where N is the total number
of elements in the dataset.
And there's another question
I want you to answer.
True or false, as we increase k
we are more likely to overfit.
I haven't told you yet
in too much detail what overfitting is.
Let me just give you a quick gist of
it so you can answer the question.
An overfit model strives really
hard to match the dataset exactly.
And then when we go on
later to use new data or
test it with test data,
it tends not to do so well.
So go for these two questions and
I'll come back in a minute and
tell you the answer.