Alright, let's start with this one.
One of these models was created
with k=N, and it's this one.
If we use all of the neighbors and all
the data points, and take their average,
the value of our model will be
the same at every single point.
Namely the mean of all the Y's
of all the data points.
So this one is b, as in bravo.
Let's do this one next, K=1.
We know that this model is going
to tag each point exactly,
because, when we're at that data point,
we'll have exactly that value.
So this model steps up and down and
tags each individual point exactly.
So that's a C, and this is, this one
is K=3, which we already looked at, A.
Okay this next question, as we increase
k we are more likely to overfit,
that is false.
In K and N, if K is equal to one,
will have the most overfit model.
And as we increase K, we're less and
less likely to overfit as we go forward.