Okay, let's start with d=1.
Well, that's a linear model.
That includes just this component.
So of course, it must be a line,
so it's gotta be this one.
That means the answer here is c.
Now we have order two and
order three to choose from.
Two is a parabola, so
it's including this component as well.
This one's a parabola of course.
And so the answer to that one is a.
And finally that leaves only b,
but let's look at why that is.
When we have a cubed component, we can
get this additional curl in there.
Now as you notice, as we increase from
order one to order two to order three,
we're gradually getting closer and
closer to tagging the actual data.
So we get to this question,
as we increase d we
are more likely to overfit.
That is true.
And in fact, it can be shown
with a polynomial like this that
as the order of the polynomial or
d reaches in,
the total number of points, we actually
can match the data at every point.
Now a couple things to note here.
One is as we go off the edge here for
all these models,
we're able to extrapolate in
the direction the data seem to be going.
And this is capability
that parametric models or
these polynomial models
have that KNN does not.