I want you now to consider
overfitting in KNN.
So in this case our horizontal
access will be K and
it could range again from 1 out to N,
the number of data points and
then the vertical access will be error.
I'm going to draw three charts here
showing N sample error as a factor of
K and
out of sample error as a factor of K.
And I want you to look at each one of
them and consider which one of them you
think is the proper representation of
what that ought to look like for KNN.
Which of these three charts
correctly represents the shape that
we would expect for out of sample
error and in sample error for
KNN, as K increases this way and
error increases that way.
So take a look and go ahead and
fill in your answer over here.