So the answer is b.
This is a little bit tricky because
the relationship for k and n and error
is a little bit different than it is for
polynomial degrees of freedom and error.
Remember that as we reduce k down to
1 our in sample error approaches 0.
In fact it becomes a 0
when k is equal to 1.
And similarly as we decrease k,
our other sample error decreases.
But at some point it begins to increase.
This one is wrong because as we
increase k, our error increases.
So this is not showing that
relationship correctly.
And this is just garbage that I threw
in there to see if anybody would bite.
[LAUGH] Now the region here in which
overfitting is occurring is here,
because remember,
as out of sample error increases, and
in sample error is decreasing,
that's where overfitting occurs