So, in terms of space for
saving the model, linear
regression is a hands down winner.
For instance, if we're learning
a third order polynomial,
we have to only store four numbers.
KNN, on the other hand,
requires you to keep all the data, so
it could be megabytes or
gigabytes of data.
So, KNN is bad in this regard.
Compute time to train.
KNN is much better in this case.
In fact,
it takes zero time to train KNN.
You just stuff the model into
a data store and you're done.
On the other hand, linear regression
has to take all that data,
compute over it,
to find those parameters.
Compute time to query.
LinReg wins hands down.
All you do is you plug your X in,
multiply it out and that's the answer.
KNN requires quite a bit of time
to query because you have to,
among other things,
usually do a sort to cross all the data.
Ease to add new data.
KNN wins that because all you
gotta do is just plop it in there,
you don't have to do any re-calculation.
With linear regression,
you have to add the new data and
then recompute the factors.
Well, that's all for
how to assess learning algorithms.
I will see you again soon.
Thank you.