Now, how does NumPy relate to Pandas?
Well, I said just a moment ago that
NumPy is a wrapper for numerical
libraries, well it turns out that
Pandas is a kind of wrapper for NumPy.
So remember our traditional data frame
here, with our columns being symbols and
our rows being dates.
This data frame is just
a wrapper around this ndarray,
access the columns with symbols and
the rows by dates.
But you can, in fact, just treat this
inside part as an ndarray directly.
If you use this syntax in Python,
that pulls these values out and
lets you access it directly and
then ndarray.
You don't really need to do that though,
you can,
if you like, treat a data frame
just like a NumPy ndarray.
And so we're going to assume
in the rest of this lesson
that we're just working with an ndarray.
And like I said, you can use all of
these mechanisms that we're going to
show you with ndarrays and
with data frames directly.
What you get if you create something
as a data frame, as we'll see in
a lesson a little bit later,
you get many, many, many more routines.
And you can treat it, like I said,
just like an ndarray but
you get a vast new number of
statistical functions and so on.