Consider an nd array, nd1.
I'm going to show you now how
to access cells within that.
Now, the notation, at first,
might seem sort of familiar, but
there's some new and different things
that you probably haven't seen before.
So the usual syntax is
the name of your nd array,
bracket, the row and the column.
So again, these are our rows.
So row indicates which row we're using.
Column, which column.
It's important to know that in NumPy,
our columns and rows begin at 0.
So this element is nd1[0,0].
It then continues of course,
1, 2, 3, 4 in the rows, and
in the columns, 0, 1, 2, 3.
Before I tell you, see if you can
guess how to address this cell.
The answer is that
this cell is nd1 [3,2],
0, 1, 2, 3, 0, 1, 2.
Now, this is probably the kind
of stuff you've seen before.
It turns out, though,
that the NumPy is much more powerful and
can do interesting and
different kinds of slicing.
What if, for instance,
you wanted to address this
sub portion of the nd array?
How could you indicate that?
NumPy uses a special symbol,
the colon, to let you indicate ranges.
So we can indicate this
range in rows with 0:3,
which indicates the zeroth to the,
just before the third row.
And in the columns, we've got 01:3.
So this syntax indicates starting
at the zeroth row to just
before the third and the first
column to just before the third.
And in fact, captures this region.
The key thing to remember here
that's a little bit tricky is that
this last value is one past the one
that you actually want to include.
So, for instance, this is column 3,
but it's not included.
Now, if we just use the colon by
itself that indicates, for instance,
if we place it in the rows position,
that we want all of the rows.
So you don't have to use the colon
just to indicate a range.
You can use it by itself for
all of them.
Now, look at this statement,
see if you can figure out
which part of this nd array it
refers to before I show you.
It is this region right here.
So it's all the rows and
column 3, 0, 1, 2, 3.
So it's this section right here.
NumPy includes some
special syntax that lets
you refer to the last row or column.
So, for instance, the last row here,
you can indicate with
negative 1,
second to last row would be negative 2.
So if we wanted to refer
to these 2 cells here,
we would take advantage of
this negative 1 syntax.
So a negative 1 indicates that last row.
And then to get these 2 columns,
we would use 1:3.
0, 1, 2, and
then we don't include the last 1 there.
There is a bunch of new syntax.
I hope that you find it exciting.
This is really one of the most
powerful aspects of Python and NumPy.
And it really enables you to
do some interesting things.
Now, we've got a quiz to see if you
can figure out how to use this new
syntax yourself.