Of these four,
this one is the right answer.
Here's why.
This is the only left-hand side that
singles out these correct rows,
starting at zero, and ending at one.
And these correct columns, again
starting at zero and ending at one.
If you look at the right hand side,
here is a little bit of new syntax
that you hadn't seen before.
We indicate the rows
second from last by a -2.
So that's what that -2 means.
And a colon with nothing after it
means go all the way to the end.
So we've singled out these rows and
this indicates these two columns.
So that's why this one
is the correct answer.
Now, I'm going to hand it over to Dev,
and
she is going to show you how to do all
these things directly in Python syntax.
Here's to you Dev.