dtype is the parameter we
passed to the function
to specify the type of the value
we want in each array location.
Here we defined the values to be
integers using NumPy data type np.int.
Just as a matter of fact,
NumPy supports a much greater variety
of numerical types than Python.
Let's run this.
Here it is.
The array now has integer values.
And since we defined the array as ones,
it has all the values as 1.
Just like function np and
ones, you can create an array full
of zeroes using the zeroes function.
All these functions accept
the dtype parameter.
Before moving forward, I would like
to mention that we can also create
n-dimensional array using
the low-level NumPy function ndarray.
But ones, zeroes and empty provide
a more friendly interface for
creating arrays.
And are hence generally preferred.
Refer to the documentation links and
instructor notes for more information.