As I mentioned, we're assuming that you
want to be a portfolio manager of some
sort and there are several different
sorts of portfolios you might manage.
So let's take a look at a few of those.
There are many different types of funds,
of course, but
three broad classes that we'll
take a look at are ETFs or
exchange-traded funds,
mutual funds, and hedge funds.
Let's look at the differences
between these.
ETFs, or exchange-traded funds,
are very much like stocks in the sense
that you can buy and sell them.
You can observe their prices intraday.
You can trade them just like
stocks on the stock exchange.
They represent baskets of stocks.
Sometimes they represent other
instruments like bonds and so on.
But it's very well-known and
they publish what it is they're holding.
Accordingly, ETFs are very
transparent and they're very liquid.
Mutual funds are somewhat similar
to ETFs in the sense that they have
a declared goal or mechanism.
In other words, they're, for instance,
trying to track the S&P 500 or
some other such goal, but
they're a little bit different.
First of all, you can only buy or
sell mutual funds at the end of the day.
So at the end of the day they add
up all the things they hold and
compute a net asset value, and
that's the value at which you can buy or
sell shares of a mutual fund.
They don't disclose exactly what they're
holding except once every quarter, so
they're accordingly less transparent.
They're less transparent because
since their last disclosure,
you don't know exactly what
they might have bought or sold.
Still, they're somewhat transparent
because they have stated goals and
you know what they're trying to achieve,
similar to, say,
an ETF that might represent the S&P 500.
There are also mutual funds
that represent large cap stocks
like the S&P 500.
Hedge funds are even less
transparent than mutual funds.
In fact,
even to buy shares in a hedge fund,
you have to enter into an agreement
that is usually secret in
the sense that you're not supposed to
reveal the contents of that agreement.
It's hard to exit a hedge fund.
They usually require you
to put your money in and
leave it there for some number
of months, sometimes years, and
when you take it out, you can't
necessarily take it out all at once.
Hedge funds don't ever have to
disclose what they're holding,
not even to the investors
in the hedge funds.
Now, that might dissuade
you from wanting, say,
to invest in it if you don't
know what they're holding.
On the other hand, you know,
if they show you a good performance,
you might want to invest.
They will usually describe to clients
what their strategy is and so
on to encourage clients to invest.
Accordingly, hedge funds
are not transparent at all.