I mentioned a couple words while I
was describing these different kinds
of funds that I wanted to
touch on real quickly.
I said liquid a couple times.
What that means is the ease
with which one can buy or
sell shares in a particular holding.
Stocks are extremely liquid.
ETFs are liquid in the same way,
in other words
you can go to a stock exchange,
you can buy an ETF and sell an ETF.
It's priced just like a stock,
but when you buy it,
you're buying shares of multiple
stocks instead of just a single stock.
But ETFs are liquid because
they're easy to trade.
They're also liquid in many
cases because there's so
much dollar value trading
in them each day.
If you look up an ETF on
say Google Finance or
Yahoo Finance, you can see how
much volume is traded each day.
And ETFs with higher volumes
are even more liquid.
I mentioned large cap.
What cap means here is capitalization or
in other words,
how much is the company
worth according to
number of shares that are outstanding,
times the price of the stock.
So, some really huge cap stocks,
say like Apple are worth many,
many billions of dollars.
So when I say large cap stocks,
that's what I'm referring to.
There's also small cap stocks that
are similarly, have lower value.
And one thing to mention as long as
we're on this topic, is the price of
a stock really only relates to
what one share is selling at.
It doesn't relate to the overall
value of the company.
We'll get into all of these
topics a little bit later.
Now to recap, there are at least
these three types of funds.
There are electronically traded funds,
which you can trade like
stocks on a stock market.
There's mutual funds, that
are a little bit harder to get in and
out of, but
you can trade them on a daily basis.
You usually have to go
through a specific broker.
You can't just trade them on your own,
and
finally hedge funds require a specific
agreement to trade into or out of.
Okay, those are the three
major types of funds.