Now as you might have discovered,
these four- or
five-letter symbols
represent particular funds.
So VTINX is a mutual fund.
DSUM is an ETF.
FAGIX is another mutual fund.
You probably discovered the Bridgewater
Pure Alpha doesn't have one of
these symbols, and
that's because it's a hedge fund.
These guys have symbols, these
short several-letter abbreviations,
so that they can trade more easily
on exchanges that have hundreds and
thousands of different assets
that are being traded.
Whereas when you go to
engage with a hedge fund,
it's just a one-on-one relationship.
Hedge funds typically have no more
than 100 investors, whereas all these
other types of symbols have thousands
and maybe even millions of investors.
Finally, SPLV is an ETF.
A couple of other things to mention.
It's fairly common practice that
mutual funds have five letters and
ETFs have four or three.
Again, you can see this
mutual fund has five letters.
And this is another
ETF with four letters.
Okay, on to more fun.