We talked already about some
of the differences between
Exchange Traded Funds,
Mutual Funds, and Hedge Funds.
And those differences that we talked
about are primarily having to do with
how they're traded and how visible, what
their holding is to those who invest.
Another very,
very important sort of difference is
how are the managers of
these funds compensated?
In other words,
there's some sort of rule for
each one that shows how
the fund managers make money.
And that's very, very important because
the manner in which they're paid
incentivizes them to trade or
act in certain ways.
So let's talk about each
one of these individually.
Before I get started, though,
I have to introduce one concept here.
It's called assets under management or
AUM.
And this is the buzz word that simply
means how much money is being managed by
the fund?
It's important because for
all of these part of the compensation
is a percentage of the AUM.
The managers of ETFs are compensated
according to an expense ratio
which is simply some percentage of AUM.
Expenditure issues for
ETFs are usually pretty low.
They vary from as low .01% or,
one bit as that might be called,
to as high as 1%.
But one that's up to 1% is
fairly high and pretty unusual.
Mutual fund managers are also
compensated using an expense ratio.
These are somewhat higher than ETFs.
They range from a low of,
typically, about 0.5%,
to some that are very high, up to 3%.
Now, what's the reason for
this difference?
Well, mutual fund managers
will tell you that
the way they manage funds
requires much more skill.
They have much more discretion
than those who are managing ETFs.
ETFs usually are tied to an index.
As an example, a popular ETF, SPY,
is supposed to track the S&P 500.
And, all that an ETF manager
has to do in that case
is just make sure that they are holding
all the stocks and the S&P 500.
Mutual funds, on the other hand,
supposedly use more skill and therefore,
they can charge a higher expense ratio
both were the cost of research and
also for their skill.
Finally Hedge funds
are completely different breed
in terms of how their
manager's are compensated.
You follow the old model called two and
twenty which means 2 or
2% of AUM, plus 20% of the profits.
So as you can see, it's higher
than both of these other methods.
And most importantly, it includes this
component relating to profits, that 20%.
Now, one or
two other things to clarify here.
What I've been talking about is
the way that the folks who manage
these funds are compensated.
Separately, if you are an investor in
one of these funds, in other words you
give your money to one of these
types of funds to be managed,
your return is based on how much
the value of that fund increased and
in most cases that increase is subject
to what happens to the economy or
what happens in the markets.
Let's look at a more detailed example
of this two and twenty structure.