Consider this example for
the 2 and 20 situation.
Assume you're a hedge fund manager and
that you've been managing a fund of
$100 million, and that over the course
of a year your skill has resulted in an
increase in value of that fund by 15%.
So over that year, the fund grew in
value from 100 million to 115 million.
What would you're compensation be?
So it's 2% of AUM plus 20% of profit.
The two component works
out to be $2 million.
The 20 component is 20%
of the $15 million profit
we made which is 3 million.
So total compensation for this year for
the hedge fund manager would
be about five million dollars.
Now one question that some people might
have is, hey is this two component
2% of 100 million or 2% of 115,
and it depends on
the hedge fund of course.
And it depends on when they take
snap shots to do accounting.
The full answer is
probably it's going to be
a blend somewhere between
100 million and 115 million.
This structure Two and
Twenty has been assailed lately
and it's very rare now to find a hedge
fund that offers rates that high.
They're much lower now.
One and Ten.
Things like that.
So the Two and Twenty was in the heyday
of hedge funds in the 90s and
early 2000s.
Nowadays they are typically
a little bit lower.
There are some Star hedge
funds that charge more.
For instance, ASC Capital, which is no
longer operating to the public anyways,
that charge as much as 40%,
so it was 4 and 40.
However, most hedge funds you find
today will be somewhere between Two and
Twenty or lower.