With regard to accumulating
assets under management,
the expense ratio approach really
most strongly motivates that.
Although I wouldn't count too much off
if you also clicked two and twenty
because of course the two part of two
and twenty is assets under management.
But, if you were strictly
driven by expense ratio,
you're going to be applying most of your
energy towards accumulating assets so
that you'll have a higher return.
In other words, as a portfolio manager,
you'll get more money.
Profits are different, ETF's and
mutual fund managers are not
compensated for making profit.
Especially when you consider,
say, ETFs, exchange traded funds.
They're just supposed to track
a particular asset or index, and
they should be good at that.
It's not up to them whether
that index goes up or down.
So two and twenty is the structure
that most compensates for profit
because it has this twenty component
that is indeed part of that profit.
With regard to risk taking,
an expense ratio
based fund really is not
incentivized to take risks at all.
If they take risks,
there's no compensation for it.
Under the two and twenty model though,
they are incentivized to take risks
because that's how they
can get to profits.
Also, because they're always
going to get this two percent,
even if they take huge risks and
don't make a profit, they're always
going to get that two percent.
So they're incentivized
to take a risk because A,
there's not too much of a penalty and
B, if they take a risk and
make profits,
then they'll be compensated more.