We're going to consider
now the intrinsic value of
our one dollar machine.
In other words, this machine
generates one dollar every year.
Now to understand that,
we need to think about what is
the future value of a dollar.
What do I mean by that?
Well, let's suppose I told you,
hey look, awesome student,
I promise I will give you $1 in a year.
How much would you pay me today
on the basis of that promise?
In other words,
maybe you would pay me 80 cents, and
then in a year I give you $1,
maybe you would pay me more.
Think for
a moment about how much you would pay me
given my promise that I'll give
you a dollar a year from now.
Okay I want you to consider
these three assets.
One of them is a dollar right now,
in other words I
pull a dollar bill out of my pocket and
I give it to you right now.
Another is, I, Tucker Balch,
promise to give you a dollar in a year.
Now that's a promise you can abide by,
you can trust me, I'm your professor,
I'm going to give you
that dollar in a year.
But what you need to think about is,
what's the value of that
promise or that bond, considering
that it won't happen for a year.
And finally, consider this
asset where the US government
promises to give you a dollar in a year.
Now I want you to rank each of
these assets, a one dollar bill,
a United States of America bond,
or a Balch promise,
a Balch bond, to pay you $1 in a year.
How would you rate these one through
three where one is the best,
where three is the worst?
How would you rank these three assets?
In other words, which would you rather
have if you had to choose one or
the other where one is the best and
three is the worst?