Think back now to our original problem.
What is the present value
of a future dollar, FV,
delivered some number of years in the
future, where i is how many years it is?
And we use IR, or the interest rate,
as a factor that affects this value.
The analogy for this to real companies
is that real companies pay dividends.
In other words,
if you own a share of a company,
you will get some cash payment
each year or each quarter.
As an example,
if you own one share of Apple stock,
it pays you about $1 a year.
Consider that you'll get that
payment every year into the future.
What is the value of
that payment over time?
What this interest rate relates
to is how risky the company is.
In other words, you're as sure that it's
going to pay you that dollar every year
as you are sure that the US government
would pay you a dollar on a bond.
Then, this IR interest rate should be
the same as the US government bond rate.
However, if you're less certain
that this company is going to
pay you at that rate, this interest
rate needs to be a little bit higher.
In other words,
you need to expect that the company is
going to pay you more in the future or
that it's going to be more likely to
pay you that dollar in the future.
This is called the discount rate.
The discount rate is higher if
you trust the company less or
you think it's more risky.
The discount rate is lower
if it's more certain to
pay you that dividend every year.
Let's suppose that after
considering all the factors,
you feel that it's
appropriate that a company
should pay you a 5% interest
rate considering its risks.
Now based on that,
if you want to calculate
what the value of the company is
based on the dividends it's paying,
you can take that into
account in the following way.
Essentially, what you want to
do is compute what is the value
of all the future dividends
that it's going to pay me?
So that's the sum of the dividend
it'll pay you in a year.
The dividend it'll pay you a year after
that, and the year after that, and
the year after that.
In fact, you want to sum those
all the way out to infinity.
So what we're looking for
is the sum of this equation,
but over all i going into the future.
We can draw on this infinite sum,
in other words for i = 1,
1 year to infinity years,
of the sum 1 over n to the i.
So this n here is this value, and
we can replace 1 here with future value.
So this is not a math class,
I'm just going to give you the answer.
The answer is that this infinite sum,
in other words,
some future dollar paid each
year in the future over
an infinite number of years,
is that value divided by n minus one.
Which is equal to future value
divided by discount rate.
So in the case of our dollar machine,
we're paying one dollar each year
in the future at 5% interest.
So the value of our dollar
machine is $20 overall.
What we've just described,
where future value is the dividend
we're going to pay at regular
intervals and DR is discount rate.
In other words,
what the risk of the stock equates to in
terms of an interest rate we should pay.
This equation tells us
the intrinsic value of the company.
In other words, if we're
going to pay that future value or
dividend every year or
every quarter going into the future,
what's the value of the company on
that basis, this is intrinsic value.
And in the example of the company
we were talking about,
that creates a $1 every year.
It's the value of the $1 in
one year from now, next year,
next year, next year, next year,
continuing ad infinitum into the future.
And that's 20 bucks.