Now I want you to try to pull all
this together that we taught you so
far in this lesson.
I'm going to give you some specific
details about a particular stock and
I want you to tell me if
you would buy that stock.
And give you information
about the company,
which has one value and the stock
which is not necessarily the same.
And I want you to tell me,
would you buy that stock.
We're going to break it into
a few individual problems,
three little problems and then we're
going to ask the big question.
We'll start with the three
little problems.
Consider this company.
It's an airline.
It owns ten airlines.
Each of them is worth 10 million.
It's got a brand name that's worth
10 million, and it's got a loan or
liability of 20 million.
All those go into the calculation
of the book value.
With regard to intrinsic value,
it pays $1 million
per year in dividends
assuming a 5% discount rate.
What's that intrinsic value?
Finally, I want you to compute the
market capitalization assuming there's
one million shares outstanding and
$75 stock price.