Now add a scatter plot for
another stock, ABC, and
again each one of these dots represents
the daily return of SPY versus ABC, and
we fit a line to it, and
it turns out it's got a slope of two, so
now we're going to ask you
a couple of questions about it.
Now add a scatter plot for
another stock, ABC, and
again each one of these dots represents
the daily return of SPY versus ABC, and
we fit a line to it, and
it turns out it's got a slope of two, so
now we're going to ask you
a couple of questions about it.
The slope is just the slope.
Correlation is a measure of
how tightly do these individual
points fit that line?
So you could have a shallow slope but
the data tightly fitting that line,
and thus a higher correlation.
Or you could have a steeper line and
the data fitting that line
at a higher correlation.
Correlation is just a measure of how
tightly do those dots fit the line.
And you can have
a correlation from 0 to 1.
Now add a scatter plot for
another stock, ABC, and
again each one of these dots represents
the daily return of SPY versus ABC, and
we fit a line to it, and
it turns out it's got a slope of two, so
now we're going to ask you
a couple of questions about it.
Now add a scatter plot for
another stock, ABC, and
again each one of these dots represents
the daily return of SPY versus ABC,
and we fit a line to it, and
it turns out it's got a slope of two, so
now we're going to ask you
a couple of questions about it.