As an illustration of how
hedge funds use CAPM,
let's consider a two stock scenario.
So our hedge fund has done some research
maybe they've used machine learning,
maybe they've used some other method or
maybe they've just thought very hard and
for whatever reason
they predict that stock
A is going to go up 1% over
the market in the next ten days.
And they've looked backwards in history
and observed that the beta for stock A,
with regard to the market, is 1.0.
So plus 1% beta of 1.0.
They've looked at another stock, B,
which they predict to go down 1%
whichever way the market goes,
it'll go 1% below it.
And the beta for stock B is 2.0.
So this introduces for the first time
this idea of a long short portfolio.
In other words, we think that stock A's
going to go up, so we should long it.
And we think stock B's going to go down,
so we should short it.
And there's some strong advantages
to this long short approach that'll
begin to emerge as we
go through this lesson.
So we're going to talk
a look at a couple scenarios
with these two stocks to see how we
should best allocate between the two.
So looking back,
this is what the S&P 500 has been doing.
Remember stock A has a beta of one,
so it follows what the S&P
500 does pretty closely.
Stock B, on the other hand, has this
beta of greater than one, or two.
And so it's reacting much
more wildly than stock A.
Here's our first scenario.
Let's assume the market stays flat,
in other words it returns 0% over
these following ten days, and that we
enter our positions as of this day and
our positions are going to be
a $50 long position in stock A and
a $50 short position in stock B.
Now assume going forward also
that our predictions are perfect.
That A goes up 1% over the market and
B goes down 1% below the market.
What will happen?
Well, if our predictions were perfect,
stock B should go down
1% below the market, and stock
A should go up 1% above the market.
What does that mean in terms of how
much money we would see returned?
So if we look at stock A, and remember
we're using the CAPM, we should expect
to see the return for A as beta of
A times return on the market plus alpha.
So, the market didn't move at all so
this gets nullified so alpha for
A is one percent and we invested
$50 in that so our return is $0.50.
Similarly for B, this element is
removed because our return was zero and
all we're left with is alpha.
Now essentially our alpha
here was negative and
we made a negative bet,
so our return is 0.5 or
altogether $1.0 or 1% for
our total investment.