Let's start by taking a look at stock A.
So, market one up 10%, we predicted
that A would go up one percent over
the market and its beta is one.
So, we should see a return of about 11%.
So, we get 11% here and $5.50 here.
B is a little bit more tricky.
Remember, B has a beta of two.
The market went up 10%, so
B's going to go up 20% minus
the one percent we thought it
would do relative to the market.
So for B,
the stock price went up 19% but,
we had a negative bet there,
so we get negative 19% here.
So, we're going to
lose $9.50 on that bet.
Now, to compute the totals here,
let's do the dollars first.
So, we made $5.50 on stock A, but
we lost $9.50 on stock B,
so altogether, we lost $4.
Now, when you calculate
the total return here,
you can't just add these two up and
get negative eight, because remember,
we only had .5 over allocation
in each one of these.
So, to get the total,
you multiply this return by .5,
that return by .5, And
you get negative four.
Yes, it's a little bit tricky.
Let's run through one more example
here just so we get it straight.
Let's assume now that
the market goes down 10%.
How does this all work out?
Stock A should only go down nine
percent, because we think it's going to
perform one percent over the market and
it's beta is one.
Stock B is going to go down 20% and
minus that one percent that we think
is going to go below the market.
So let's talk B is going to go down 21%.
So we're going to lose nine percent or
$4.50 on stock A,
but we're going to really
kick butt on stock B.
Stock B went down 21%, but
remember we shorted it, so
we're going to get all together $10.50.
So all together we're going to
win six dollars or six percent.
What's the take away here?
The take away is even if we have
perfect alpha and perfect beta,
if we're not careful about how we
allocate our money, we can still lose.
How can we fix this?
The CAPM can help.