Let's pull out the CAPM and
take a look at this portfolio.
Remember for each individual stock,
the expected return is
beta times return on the market
plus alpha times the weight for
that particular stock and when we're
short, the weight is negative.
And we do this across
the stocks in our portfolio.
And then, that's our expected return for
the portfolio.
So, I'm going to expand this sum.
First, I'm going to start
with the beta component.
So we get, weight a times beta b,
plus weight b times beta b,
times return on the market.
So recall the numbers from earlier.
Our weights for A and
B were each .5 and -.5.
We got a beta of 1.0 for
A and a beta of 2.0 for B.
For our alphas we had plus 1% for
stock A and -1% for stock B.
We can plug all these into
our equation and work it out.
For our beta component, we end up
with a beta for the portfolio of -.5.
Our alpha component for
stock A ends up just being .5 and
for stock B, -.5 times -1 or .5.
Bringing it all together
under these assumptions,
using the CAPM, our expected return for
this allocation is -.5
times a market return + 1%.
Let's double-check this by plugging
in one of our earlier examples.
Consider that example where
the market went up 10%.
So we've got -.5 times 10% + 1%.
So in the case where
the market goes up 10%,
we expect a -4% return for
our portfolio.
So if you step back a little bit,
remember that we arrived at
this 1% using information.
So we have some information about these
stocks that lead us to believe one would
go up 1% over the market, another
would go down 1% over the market.
On the other hand, we don't really have
any knowledge about what's going
to happen for the market over all.
So we have no control
over this component.
Is there some way that
we can remove this?
Can we make this part equal to 0?
If we can do that, then we essentially
remove market risk from our portfolio.
And we preserve this 1% over here.
Well, the way to do that
is to focus on this part.
Remember, this is beta for
the portfolio.
Can we make beta for the portfolio = 0?
Or in other words,
can we find weights for A and B,
such that their sum turns out to be 0?
What are these two weights so
that the overall portfolio beta is 0?