Okay, so we want to find two weights,
A and B.
Such that when you multiply them by
their betas, the sum turns out to be 0.
Now keep in mind,
that we're going to short B, so
this one needs to be negative.
And we're going to long A, so
this one needs to be positive.
Just keep that in mind as we go forward
so, let's solve for A initially here.
So we know that the weight of A should
be equal to -2 times the weight of B.
We also know that the sum of A and
B, well the sum of the absolute values
of A and B, should be equal to 1.
If we plug thi minus 2 weight of B and
for weight of A we get this,
or long story short.
The absolute value
the weight of B = 1/3.
So I know the weight of B has to be
negative, so we get minus one third for
the weight of B.
And coming all the way back up here,
we know that the weight of A is equal
to Negative two times the weight of B.
So we get this.
So finally, the answers are: 2/3 for
the weight of A.
-1/3 for the weight of B.