Okay we've calculated these weights.
Let's see how they work on
the examples we've been looking at.
So again our weight for
stock A is going to be .66 and for
stock B is going to be negative .33.
And we're going to look at this
scenario where the market goes up 10%.
We'll pull out our old trusty CAPM and
expand it for these two stocks.
So for
stock A we have the weight of stock A,
times its beta times the return on
the market, plus the alpha component.
So these are the two parts that relate
to the return on the market, and
we'll bring them together.
So for stock A we have 0.66,
and our beta is 1.0.
And for stock B we've got -0.33 times
2 times the return on the market.
So because of all that work we
did to figure out these values,
we know already that this
is going to become 0.
We'll carry down our two alpha
components, so for stock A,
our alpha expectation is 1%,
and our weighting is 0.66.
For stock B,
our weighting is negative one third,
times -1, our expectation is
just going to go down 1.0%.
So combining these two, 0.66 plus
0.33 gives us a 1.0% expected return.
Whichever way the market goes.
Remember, we eliminated
the return on the market.
So, whichever way the market goes,
we can expect to get 1% return.
Now, need to add a lot of caveats here.
These betas aren't necessarily fully
guaranteed to continue into the future,
and these alphas aren't guaranteed,
either.
These are just estimates that we
computed based on information we thought
we had, so this is not a guaranteed
thing by any means, but
it is a way to use long/short investing
to reduce exposure to the market overall
and to focus on those alpha components
where we do have information.