Let's bring it all together now, how
hedge funds can use CAPM effectively.
Assuming we have some sort
of actionable information
that we can convert into a forecast
alpha, in other words, a prediction for
a particular stock i,
about which way it's going to go.
And also the beta of that stock
with regard to the market.
We can do the following.
We can minimize market
risk by finding a beta for
our portfolio that's equal to zero.
And we can do that by finding
the appropriate weights
on each individual stock.
So, CAPM can be a really valuable tool
in terms of portfolio construction
because it can enable you
to build these portfolios
that are less exposed to market risk.
And this is where the whole idea
of long short trading came about.
You know,
CAPM really enables you to refine that.
All right, that is it for now.
We'll see you again soon.
Thank you.