So in order to get to
a dataframe like this,
we've got a couple of problems to solve.
And we're going to solve
them in this lesson.
So one of the first issues is we want
to be able to read in particular
date ranges.
So if you remember from the last lesson,
we just read all of it in.
But what if we just want to
read in a certain part of it,
instead of from 1995 to 2012.
What if we want, say, just 2010 to 2012?
Well, we gotta figure
out how to solve that.
Something that's very special about
Pandas, and one of the things
that makes it very powerful,
is that we can index the rows by dates.
We don't have to just use a single
number like zero for instance.
We need to be able to read in multiple
stocks, instead of just, say having one.
We want to have SPY, IBM,
Google, and Gold all at once.
We need to be able to align dates.
For instance,
If GLD traded on particular days and
SPY traded on particular days we want
to make sure that those line up, so
that for each row we have
the correct information for
each equity on that particular date.
Finally, we need to undo that problem
that we discovered in the last lesson.
Namely that these dates and the files
we read them from are in reverse order.
So, we want to be sure that we have
them in the right order when we're
processing them.
So, these are the tasks we're
going to dig into in this lesson.