Now here's how we're going to
build that data frame.
Alright we start by constructing
an empty data frame
that has all the dates we're
potentially interested in.
And Dave will show you the syntax for
doing that later on in the lesson.
We'll call this df1 for
data frame 1 of course.
Now, we want to load this data frame up
with a column of data for SPY, for IBM,
for Google and Gold, and I'm going to
show you step by step how we do that.
Okay, so we separately read in SPY.
And again,
Dave will show you how to do that.
Now when we read SPY,
we get all the potential dates and
all the prices that go with that.
And in this case,
we're loading adjusted closed data.
Note that there's many more
dates here than there are here.
And this is our target data frame that
we loaded with the particular dates
that we're interested in.
One other thing to mention,
that I didn't mention before,
is these two days are weekend days.
So you can go ahead and
check your calendar, go back to 2010,
and see if I'm right.
Interesting thing, or
just obvious thing about weekends,
is the markets are not open on weekends.
So if you compare this with this,
look in our SPY history,
we don't have the 23rd and the 24th
because SPY did not trade that day.
So, we've got a little bit of mismatch
there that we need to deal with.
And this actually is one of
the important reasons that we use SPY
as a reference, because if SPY traded,
it meant the market was open.
And if the market was open, SPY traded.
So, SPY, the S&P 500 ETF,
is our reference for many, many things.