So pandis has many
very powerful features,
among those features are the ability to
do many operations that you may
be familiar with from databases.
In particular, one that we're
going to leverage here is adjoin.
So we're going to join this data
from SPY and our empty data frame.
And we're going to do a special
join that says, look,
we're only interested in dates that
are present both in SPY and df1.
And what happens is,
we end up with this data.
According to its date and
this position in our target dataframe,
and, of course,
the other two rows as well.
But note, because of the join,
these two days were missing from SPY and
the result of the join is they
are eliminated from our dataframe.
They're eliminated
because it's the weekend.
There was no trading, because we know
that because SPY is our reference.
All right, so here's our original data
frame now after we've loaded an SPY.
And those weekend days that were
here are gone because of that join.
Now we can add more
columns from other stocks,
here's one for instance, IBM,
by performing additional joins.
So after this join with data frame IBM,
bump,
we've got this new data over
here in our empty data frame.
We can repeat this process for each
additional symbol that we want to add.
So we'll add Google and GLD.
And again, Dave will show you
the syntax for doing that and
pandis in just a few moments.