Let's try to build the data
frame professor outline.
Starting with the things we need to
populate the data frame with, r,
firstly dates.
We used pandas date range method
which takes two parameters,
that is start and end date.
For this code,
we will take a small date range that is
from 22nd Jan 2010 to 26th Jan 2010.
We then call the date range
function as I mentioned before,
passing two parameters,
start date and the end date.
Let's run this code to see
what variable dates has in it.
The output you see is not
the list of strings, but
the list of date time index objects.
Now, what do you mean by
date time index object?
Let's extract the foremost
element of this list.
You can get the forced element
of the list by writing
dates[0] Let's go ahead and
run this code.
This is the first element of the list
which a date/time index object.
The trailing zero zeros for
each object is the default time stamp.
The index for
a stock data only consists of dates.
We can ignore the time stamps for now.
Next we define an empty dataframe
df1 with these dates as index.
We use the parameter index
to supply the dates.
Note that without this parameter the
dataframe will have an index of integers
0,1,2 as seen before.
Let's print this now.
So here's your DataFrame, DF1.
It's an empty DataFrame with no columns.
However, as we pass the index parameter,
we have an index as dates.
And you can see that it's
a date time index object.
Two major steps have now been completed.