You must have noticed how we
are carrying out essentially the same
operation in different places.
Why not write some utility function
that we can use going forward?
I have implemented one function for
you, symbol_to_path.
It accepts a symbol name as a string and
returns the path to the corresponding
CSV file, assuming it is
stored under data by default.
For example, symbol_to_path
IBM will return data/IBM.csv.
Can you finish the implementation for
get_data?
It take a list of symbols and
dates as index and is supposed to return
a data frame with stock data for
each symbol within the given date range.
SPY is inserted into the list,
if not already present,
in order to solve as a reference.
Note that you must ensure the column for
SPY does not have any nulls.
That is, the data frame should only
contain dates when SPY actually traded
in the given date range.
Type in your code here.
You can use test run to
execute your code and
submit to evaluate it
against our test cases.
Don't worry, there is no limit
to how many times you can try.
Good luck.