As show in the previous demo,
there are three main steps to
implement inside the for loop.
The first one is to read in
the data from the symbol.
Make sure you specify
all the parameters.
Also notice how I have used
symbol_to_path function
to get the path to the CSV file.
The next step is to rename the adjacent
close column to the symbol name.
And the last step is to join this
new data with the new data frame.
Now, we have to take care
of one important thing.
That is,
dropping off the lines from the SPY.
Subset is equal to SPY will ensure that
only those rows will be
dropped where SPY is none.
Also the statement ensures that
SPY is used as a reference.
And that we do not have any
non-values in the SPY column.
Let's run it.
So here's the output, same as before.