Okay, let's suppose we have a nice
big beautiful pandas dataframe and
this time read in a lot of data.
We didn't just focus on a few days,
we've got the data all the way from
the beginning of 2010 to 2012 and we
got data for SPY, IBM, Google and GLD.
Now suppose we want to focus
on just a subset of that data.
In fact, we might call that a slice.
For instance, what if we wanted
to look at just the values for
Google and GLD between these dates,
February 13,
2010 through February 15, 2010, and
we want to again just look at Google and
GLD.
Well there's very beautiful syntax in
Pandas that allows you to do that.
So we're going to be learning a lot more
about this syntax in a later lesson.
But this is sort of a preview of
the very nice things you can do.
To select these rows we do a simple
statement that they will show
you later to create a date time object.
And we just put the start
date colon end date.
And if we just write df1[sd:ed] where
this is start date and that's end date,
then we end up With these three rows,
but we want to be more selective.
We want to focus on these three rows and
these columns and
we need to add one more piece of
syntax that indicates these columns.
So this statement will extract
these rows and these columns,
and leave you just with this
sub-portion or slice of df1.
So, if we were to execute
the statement df2 equals df1,
and then this additional syntax,
we will end up with this
little morsel of data right
here in our new dataframe.
Now there's lots of different ways
you can slice the data, you don't
have to take a group of pieces of data
that are right next to each other.
You can grab any different columns you
want and any different rows you want.
So you might build a new
dataframe by taking GLD and IBM.
And it'll just take those two
columns and splat them into df2.
So that's slicing.
This is just a brief introduction.
We're going to go into some
deeper examples when we get
to the lesson on numbpie.