Suppose you've got a data frame.
It's pretty easy from the data
frame to make a plot.
In fact the syntax is as simple as this.
Pandas will take this data and create
a nice chart that looks about like this.
It will give an individual
color to each time series and
give you a nice legend
telling you which is which.
Now one problem with viewing.
Data like this is for instance,
at this time, by the way,
these numbers are made up.
But it's often the case that stocks
are priced at significantly different
levels, so in this example, say,
Google had a very high price and
the other stocks had low prices, and
it's hard to look at them sort of In
a good way comparatively when they
have these widely variant prices.
So what we'd like to do instead is
be able say to have them all start
at one single point here,
say that's 1.0.
And then go out from there so
we can compare them on
an apples to apples comparison.
So we'd like to end up with a chart
that looks like this, where everything
starts at 1.0, and we can compare
them on an equal basis going forward.