Well, it was a little bit of
a trick question because both
of these will accomplish the same goal,
namely normalizing everything
according to the first row.
This method uses two nested four
loops to go through each date for
each symbol and then make the division.
This is the preferred method however,
and
that's because it's elegant,
just a single line.
We divide the entire data
frame by its first row.
The other reason that this is the way to
do it is because it's much much faster.
This ends up being executed
in C at lower levels.
Whereas this will be executed
at the higher level,
the higher interpreter
levels of Pandas and Python