Carly Fiorina rightly states that
the goal is to turn data into
information and
information into insight.
So let's better understand
the data by improving our plots.
We will need the matplotlib library for
this purpose.
Specifically we import
the matplotlib.pyplot and
rename it as plt for ease of use.
First, let's define
a trivial plot function.
We define a plot data function
which will essentially plot
the contents of the data frame.
We pass the data frame to it and
use its plot function to
plot all the data in it.
Let's see the output.
Remember, to see the graph,
we have to call the show function
from the matplotlib library.
Observe that x axis has dates and y
axis has prices for all the four stocks.
The graph still looks incomplete.
We need to add details
like give a name or
title to the graph,
add x and y axis labels.
We will give name to the graph
by passing in parameter title.
This should be customizable.
And here we pass the value of the title
to the parameter title of the dataframe.
For x and y axis labels,
we need a handler to the plot
which the dataframe generates.
The output of df.plot is such a handler.
You can imagine it as an object.
We name it ax for axis.
Now we call set x label and
set y label on this object to give the x
and y axis some meaningful labels.
The desired labels are passed as a
parameter to the function set_xlabel and
set_ylabel.
Remember that set_xlabel and
set_ylabel are the function of
the object that we got from df.plot.
You can also use the fontsize parameter
in df.plot to make
the graph more readable.
Now let's see the modified plot.
So here is your detailed plot with
x label, y label, and a title.