Let's analyze the graph that we
had plotted for the four stocks.
You see the four stocks
are all multiple ranges.
But we need to observe
the movement of the stock.
By movement I mean how
much the stock went up or
down as compared to the others.
To do this, we need to normalize
the prices of all the stock.
We do this by dividing
the values of each column.
By day one.
This will ensure that all
the stocks will start with $1.
Power of pandas and Python is
that we can do this in one line.
Let's add it.
We define the function: normalize data
and pass the data frame through it.
First, we want all the values
of the data frame.
Hence, we just type the name of
the data frame, which is df.
Now we want to divide all
the values of this data frame
by the first row of eight.
So we extract the first
row using row slicing.
This will give us the first row.
Now we will just divide it.
Let's see how the graph changes.
Observe, all the stocks
start with price one.
And now you can see the changes
that is the stock movement.
That's it for now,
I will be back soon with more coding.
Until then, enjoy the power of
the Python and happy coding.