So I'd like you to consider two data
sets, and think about whether it
would be best to use a parametric
model or a non-parametric model.
Our first problem is a cannon,
and we orient the cannon up or
down a certain number of degrees,
and we want to estimate based on
how many degrees up or down it is how
far is the cannonball going to go.
The cannon's oriented at
a certain angle, boom,
the cannonball comes out, and
it follows some trajectory like this,
and [SOUND] splats over here,
so this angle theta is our x,
and this distance,
how far it went, is our y.
And so we take the cannon,
we orient it at many different thetas,
and we measure how far
the cannonball goes.
And that's our data.
Here's another problem
from animal behavior.
Let's suppose we have a beehive, and
we want to estimate
the behavior of the bees.
In other words, how many of them
will be attracted to this food
source as richness of
the food source increases?
So in other words, our x is
the richness of the food source, and
our y is how many.
So the reason this is a different
sort of problem than,
say, that cannonball problem,
is it's not clear that as we
increase the richness of the food,
that necessarily more bees will come.
Consider these two problems.
The cannonball problem, we're trying to
build a model for how far will the canon
ball go depending on what is x,
the angle at which the barrel is aimed.
And the honeybee problem, how many
honeybees will visit a food source
as we change the richness of the food
source from, say, poor to rich.
Do you think this problem is best
solved by a parametric model,
or non-parametric model for each one?
So go ahead and enter your guesses and
I'll tell you what I
think the answer is.