So in my view, this type of problem is
best solved by a parametric learner,
and this sort of problem is best
solved by a non-parametric learner.
And here's why.
For this problem,
you can start with an equation,
you can look it up on the net or
whatever.
That will express an estimate of how far
a cannon ball will go given this angle.
What's missing are some
parameters of that equation
that reflect the velocity of
the cannon ball coming out and so on.
But just by taking certain measurements
of how far the ball goes at different
angles, you can use a parametric
learner to find those parameters.
The key thing here is that you
can start with an estimate
of the underlying behavior of the system
in terms of a mathematical equation that
expresses how it behaves.
Now, in the cases of the honey bees,
we really don't know, we don't really
have a guess of what that underlying
mathematical equation might look like.
And if you don't have a guess,
it's better to use a non-parametric or
instance-based model because
it can fit any sort of shape.
Another way to put that is
that this model is biased, in
the sense that we have an initial guess
of what the form of the equation is.
This solution is unbiased
because we don't know.
Now, we're raised to think biased
is a bad thing, but if you go into
the problem already knowing the form
of the solution, it makes sense to take
advantage of that bias, and
aim your solution toward that bias.
Let's reflect on the pros and
cons of each approach.
For a parametric approach, we don't
have to store the original data, so
it's very space efficient, but
we can't easily update the model
as more data is gathered.
Usually we have to do a complete rerun
of the learning algorithm to update
the model, thus for
parametric approaches,
training is slow but querying is fast.
For non-parametric approaches,
or instance-based,
we have to store all the data points.
So it's hard to apply when
we have a huge data set, but
new evidence can be added easily since
no perimeters need to be learned,
adding data points doesn't consume
additional time, thus training is fast,
but querying is potentially slow.
Most importantly, these nonparametric
approaches avoid having to assume
a certain type of model, whether
it's linear or quadratic or so on.
And therefore, they're suitable
to fit complex patterns where we
don't really know what
the underlying model is like.