The correct answer is that the stock
is probably going to go down in price,
because there's much
more selling pressure.
Imagine for
a moment if we put in two market orders.
Suppose there was a market
order to sell 500 shares.
What would happen?
Boom, you would sell 100 at 99.95,
50 at 99.90 and
so on,
the price would immediately go down.
Consider on the other hand if someone
put in a market order to buy 500 shares,
well the price wouldn't budge.
You'd just get 500 of these 1000 for
sale but
the price would still remain
between $100 and 99.95.
I'll explain that a little bit more as
we provide some specific examples on
what happens to the order book
as different orders come in.