Now, as you might have guessed,
the data isn't really pristine.
So, here's what people think
financial data is like.
They imagine that it's perfectly
recorded minute by minute.
The prices that are recorded
are exactly right.
The volume data is exactly right.
But that's not the case.
But that's not the only mistake
[LAUGH] people make about
what they think the data's like.
People assume there's
no gaps in the data,
that we have every
single minute recorded.
That data for stocks started
since the beginning of time, and
they continue to the very last minute.
The reality is that our data is
an amalgamation created from many,
many sources.
For instance, for any particular stock,
it may be traded on the New York Stock
Exchange, at NASDAQ, at Bats, and
over any particular
minute during the day,
it may trade at one price at New York
Stock Exchange, another price at NASDAQ.
The reality is that there's
no single price for
any stock at any particular time.
In fact, it's hard to say who's right.
So, the reality of the data that
we get is that it's a combination
from all these different sources.
And different data providers will
provide, actually, different numbers.
And finally, one part of reality
that's especially troublesome
is not all stocks trade everyday.
Sometimes stocks come into existence and
suddenly, there's values for them and
before that there was no data.
Sometimes stocks go out of existence and
suddenly,
they quit existing and
there's no data for them going forward.
There's another kind of failure mode or
missing data mode where
a particular stock will be trading,
data will be missing, suddenly,
it starts trading again.
And these are the sorts of problems
we're going to take a look at and
find a way to solve in this lesson.