Okay, let's take a look
at some examples so
we can see how prices
are recorded over time.
We'll start with SPY.
This is showing a time series
of that ETF over time.
This is the downturn in 2008, 2009.
SPY represents the S&P 500.
It's one of the most liquid and
actively traded ETFs out there, and
we typically use it as a reference,
a time and
date reference for other stocks.
Because we know if SPY was trading,
the stock market was open and
we can use its time history as
a reference in that regard.
It goes all the way back to 1993.
There are of course some
stocks that go back further,
all the way to 1901 and so on.
But most of what we're going to do,
it's fine that we know it's
been active since 1993.
Now Let's look at
a couple more examples.
We'll add JAVA, J-A-V-A, and
as you can see, it was trading
from the beginning here but for some
reason or another, abruptly stopped.
Now what happened there?
Well, you may remember
that Sun Microsystems,
which was trading under the ticker JAVA,
was acquired by Oracle in 2010.
And on that date, that ticker went away.
So if you look at historical data for
JAVA, you'll see that it
ends at sometime in 2010.
Something else that's interesting
about this ticker JAVA,
is that before it was Sun Microsystems
it was actually Mr. Coffee.
So if you look historically for data for
JAVA you'll find two
different time series.
One for when it traded as Mr.
Coffee and another
when it traded as Sun Microsystems,
but it doesn't exist any longer.
So imagine if you're processing
this time series data,
and you arrive at this abrupt end for
JAVA, what's going to happen?
Well in the data you'll see NAN,
meaning not a number,
meaning there's no data there.
And the focus of this lesson
is what to do about that.
Let's take a look at another example.
Okay, we've added now an additional set
of data, and as you can see we named
it FAKE meaning this example we invented
for the purpose of this discussion.
Now, each of these symbols
is available to you
in the data that we provide you for
the class.
So you also will have this FAKE1.
Now, the data represented by FAKE1 is
fairly common, and we only invented
it just so it would work out well in
this chart that we're looking at.
Anyways, what's going on with FAKE1 is,
as you can see,
it didn't exist before this time.
So instead of having, for instance,
NAN values after a certain date,
this FAKE1 data is going to have
NAN values before a certain date.
So we'll have a different kind of
problem trying to process that data.
Now we'll look at one more example,
and as you might have guessed,
we named that FAKE2.
Now what's special about this one,
is it's got all of the different
kinds of problems at once.
So it didn't exist before this date,
data was absent in between
these two dates, and so on.
This is not typical data for
a very liquid,
very large stock, for
instance like Google or Apple, but
indeed data like this exists for
thinly traded stocks.
In other words, companies that don't
have a high market capitalization,
and they trade very little
if at all occasionally.
So we still have to be able to deal
with data like this in our studies,
and so
let's focus on this FAKE2 example.