Thanks, Professor,
I'll take it from here.
So hello, everyone, and
we will be using Pandas fillna
function to fill the missing data.
So let's find the documentation of this
function, and let's go to this site.
So here it is.
The link is included in
the instructor notes.
I encourage you to bookmark this site.
So it gives the usage for any function
at a glance and it will help you a lot.
So let's scroll down and
let's search for
a function using this small search box.
Let's search for fillna.
Here it is, DataFrame.fillna function,
and we'll be using this.
Read and
try to understand different options and
how to call this fillna function, and
I'll be right back with a pop quiz.
So here's a question for you.
How would you call fillna() to
fill forward missing values?
Go ahead and
type your answer in this box.