So, let's do some coding.
To start with, let's use an example
stock with missing values.
We will be using fakedo.csv and this
file is included in your data folder.
So as usual, we will be reading
the csv into the data frame and
we will do some plotting.
So now let's go and
plot this data and see what turns up.
So, here is the graph.
For the given range of dates,
you can notice that there is a gap in
the beginning and also a gap at
multiple places in the middle.
So now, let's try to fix this.
We only need to add a single
statement to fill those gaps.
As you must have read
in the documentation,
method ffill corresponds
to forward filling and
inplace is equal to TRUE will save all
the changes in the same data frame.
Try removing this and see what happens.
Now, let's plot and
see how the graph looks now.
So here's the graph.
If you look closely, you will
observe the forward filling effect.
The stock prices retained their
previous values throughout.
However, note that the missing
values at the beginning of the range
have not been filled.
Think about what you need
to do to take care of that.