Okay, consider that state s and
a are somewhat fixed.
What we're trying to find is given s and
a,
what's the probability
of a particular s prime?
So, we'll begin this by just
consulting how many times
did this transition occur?
In other words, how many times when
we were in state s did action a,
did we end up in s'?
So that's how many times this
particular transition occurred.
Now we just need to divide it by the
total number of times we were in state
s and did action a.
So essentially, it's the sum over i.
Where we have i iterate over all
the possible states of T[s, a, i].
So this is the number of times in total
that we were in state s and
executed action a.
And so this ratio ends up being
the probability that will end up in s'
if we're in state s and take action a.