Now consider rewards for our learner.
Of course it makes sense that
rewards should relate in some
way to the returns of our strategy.
There are at least two
approaches that we can utilize.
Short-term rewards in
terms of daily returns or
long-term rewards that reflect
the cumulative return of a trade cycle
from a buy to a sell, or for
shorting from a sell to a buy.
So consider these two, daily returns,
where each day we get a reward
which is equal to the return
over the last day, or
a reward where our the reward is equal
to zero, until we exit the position.
Then the cumulative return that we
gained across that whole trade.
Which one of these do you think
will result in faster conversions?