Adjusted close is not a good factor for
learning,
because you're not able to
generalize over different price
regimes for when the stock
was low to when it was high.
Also, if you're trying
to learn a model for
several stocks at once and
they each hold very different prices,
adjusted close doesn't serve
well to help you generalize.
Same thing is true for
simple moving average.
However if you combine adjusted close
and simple moving average together into
a ratio that makes a good
factor to use in state.
Bollinger Band value is also good.
P/E ratio is good.
And a new kind of feature that we're
considering here with reinforcement
learning, is whether we're
holding the stock or not.
That's an important state to know,
in other words,
if you're holding the stock it may
be advantageous to get rid of it.
But if you're not holding it,
you might not necessarily want to sell.
So this additional feature about
what your situation is is useful.
Similarly, return since we entered
the position might be useful.
In other words,
this might help us set exit points for
instance, maybe we've made 10% on
the stock since we bought it and
we should take our
winnings while we can.
So both of these are important and
good factors to have
an acute learning system.