Before we launch into details of
the capital assets pricing model,
we have to lay down
a little bit of groundwork.
Let's start with
the definition of a portfolio.
A portfolio is a weighted set of assets.
So as an example, let's suppose
you've got a portfolio that's got
three different assets in it,
Apple, Google, and Oracle.
And if you look at the entire value
of your portfolio, let's suppose that
60% of it is in Apple,
20% is in Google, and 20% is in Oracle.
If we consider this as a set of weights,
that means we've got
0.6 in Apple, 0.2 in Google and
0.3 in oracle.
So, the first part of our
definition of a portfolio
is that w sub i is the proportion
of funds that are an asset i.
We require that the sum of all
these w sub i is equal to 1,
in other words they add up to 100%.
Now sometimes, for leveraged
portfolios that we're not going to
cover in this class,
this number might be greater than one.
But skip that for now.
We do allow that you
might short some stocks.
So for instance,
let's suppose you shorted Google.
Your allocation there would be,
minus point two.
So, let's refine this
equation a little bit and
require that the sum of the absolute
value of the weights is equal to one.
So, some of them might be short,
some of them might be long.
But, if you add up the absolute value
their weights will require that to be
1.0.
So now that we've defined what
a portfolio is, let's think for
a moment about what will the returns
on a portfolio look like.
So, it's a simple equation, really.
It's the sum for
each asset of the weight of
that asset in the portfolio, times
the return for that day, of the asset.
We just add all those up,
one by one, and boom,
that's the return on the portfolio for
that day.