So a concept that's important to
the capital assets pricing model
is this thing called
The Market Portfolio.
Now what is that exactly?
When someone refers to the Market
what they're usually referring to is
an index that broadly covers
a large set of stocks.
In the US,
best example of that is the S&P500.
The S&P 500 represents the 500
largest companies that
are traded on exchanges, and
that index changes each day according
to the prices of all of its components.
There's similar indexes in
the United Kingdom, Japan,
any country or large market has
indexes that represent this.
Now, these indexes are composed of many,
many individual stocks, and
the market portfolio is a combination
of those stocks in a certain weighting.
Most of the important indexes
are what we call Cap Weighted.
And what that means is the individual
weight of each stock in the portfolio
is set according to that
stock's market cap.
So, market cap, if you recall,
stands for Market Capitalization, and
it's simply the number of shares
available for the stock times its price.
So to calculate the weight for
any particular stock, you take its
market cap and divide it by the sum
of the market caps of all the stocks.
Now, if you think back to my example
of the CEO living on an island
building his product, and there
being many islands and an ocean and
when market forces rise of fall
that affect all of the islands,
you can think of these large indexes
essentially as being an ocean.
Now within each of these oceans if you
like, there are a number of sectors.
For instance, in the US we typically
break the market into ten different
sectors, I list four of them here.
Energy, technology,
manufacturing, finance and so on.
And these are essentially the islands.
So, if some malaise occurs to,
say, energy stocks,
you can think of that as something
bad happening to the energy island.
These things might be
Saudi Arabia is pumping more oil,
so the cost of oil is going to go down.
That usually would have
a negative impact on energy, so
the energy island would
be negatively impacted.
Same thing with these other sectors.
The main point here being that positive
and negative news can affect each of
these sectors individually without
necessarily affecting the others.
So it's not unusual to break up these
large markets into individual sectors.
Now just recapping before we depart,
when we talk about the market
portfolio in this class, we are almost
always talking about the S&P 500.
And that market portfolio
consists of 500 stocks,
the largest stocks in the U.S.
that are traded publicly,
with a weighting set like this.
One thing to keep in mind Is some stocks
have surprisingly large weightings.
For instance, Apple and
Exxon each are about 5% of the S&P 500.
So those two stocks have a strong
effect on what happens to this index.
There are smaller stocks
that comprise say only
a tenth of a percent of
the overall effect on this market.