We're finally able now to get to
the core of the capital assets pricing
model, and that's expressed in this
single equation that's really important.
You need to memorize it and
understand it.
And here's what that equation is.
So the capital assets pricing
model says that the return for
an individual stock on a particular day
t = beta times the return on the market.
So, I told you just a moment ago,
for instance, that the, when we say
the market in the United States,
we're usually referring to the S&P 500.
And this particular stock, i,
is one of the stocks in the S&P 500.
So its return on a particular day,
again, is beta times the return
on the market of that day + alpha of
that particular stock on that day.
So what the capital assets pricing model
is asserting, and this is important,
is that a significant
portion of the return for
a particular stock is due to the market.
In other words, the market moving up or
down strongly affects the change in
price on every individual stock.
And the extent to which the market
affects a particular stock
is encapsulated in this beta which
we'll talk about in just a second.
But every stock has its individual beta
that specifies how much it's affected.
Many stocks have a beta near one which
means when the market goes up or
down 1%, that stock goes up or down 1%.
But if you had say a larger beta, say
two, that means if the market goes up 1%
we would expect, all else being equal,
that the stock goes up 2%.
This other component, alpha,
is called the residual.
So of course, if you look at
all the stocks over one day and
look at how much the market goes up or
down, and
you calculate how much the stock should
have gone up or down according to beta.
Well there'll be something left over.
It won't exactly match
what beta predicted.
And that's what this alpha or
residual component is.
An important part of
the capital assets pricing
model is that the expectation for
alpha is 0.
Essentially this is a random variable
with an expected value of 0.
It's important to remember that.
Where do we get this beta and
this alpha?
Well, it comes from daily returns and
essentially how the daily returns for
a particular stock relate to
the daily returns of the market.
So look at returns here for S&P 500, and
consider the S&P 500 in comparison
to this other stock xyz.
So xyz, its daily returns
are shown here in green.
And blue shows S&P 500.
Now look at each day, seems that
the xyz stock is more reactive.
In other words, if S&P 500 goes up
a little, this stock goes up more.
And, on average, it tends to
have a higher return each day.
We can look at what happens with
the returns on each day and
plot them over here in a scatter plot.
So on this particular day,
the market went up a little bit, and
xyz went up a little bit more.
So that would correspond to
a point right about there.
Now, if we plotted the results for a lot
of these days, we would get a scatter
plot that looks a bit like this,
where each green dot represents one day.
And if we fit a line to it, we'd get
something that looks about like this.
So beta is simply
the slope of this line, and
alpha is simply this area here, in other
words, the y-intercept of that line.
Now this is an after
the fact of calculation.
In other words, just because
historically a particular stock,
looking back at time gave
you a particular alpha,
you shouldn't necessarily
expect that in the future.
And again, CAPM says that you
should expect this to be 0.
In reality though, it's not always 0.
So, that's the key to the capital
assets pricing model and where beta and
alpha come from.