Now you may have heard
about the debate of
passive investing versus
active investing.
This question about passive versus
active didn't really exist before
the capital assets
pricing model came out.
And I'll explain why in just a moment.
But let me just briefly tell you
about passive versus active.
So passive essentially says that you
should just buy an index portfolio.
Like buy something that
represents the S&P 500, and hold.
Just sit on it and let it grow.
Active portfolio managers don't
just buy the index portfolio,
they pick individual stocks.
Another way you can think of this is
if you compare the active managers
portfolio to the index.
You'll find that he or
she has higher weights for
some stocks and
lowers weights for other stocks.
Of course those weights could be zero,
or even negative.
But the general idea here is that
the active portfolio manager's portfolio
differs from the market portfolio
by selecting different
weights on different stocks.
Let's return now to the capital
asset pricing model here, and
consider passive versus
active in that context.
Both active managers and
passive managers agree with
this part of the equation.
In other words,
however the stock moves each day is most
significantly influenced by the market,
and that the amount that it moves
is strongly related to beta.
Where they differ is with regard
to their treatment of alpha.
The CAPM says two important
things about alpha.
First, it's random.
You can't predict it, and
the expected value is zero.
Some days it'll be positive,
some days it'll be negative.
It may be large, it may be small,
but it's random.
And on average,
it's value is going to be zero.
Active managers, on the other hand,
believe they can predict alpha.
In other words,
they can compare two stocks and
they say I think this one is going to
go up relative to the market.
Remember, this alpha is market-relative.
Or, I think this other stock is going to
go down relative to the market.
Now, they might not be exactly
right on every single pick.
But they believe on average they're
better than just flipping a coin.
So if you believe what active managers
say, you can use information and perhaps
machine learning to find stocks that
have either positive or negative alpha.
And you can use that information
to select your stock picks.
And we'll show some
examples of that later on.
Anyways, if you believe the capital
assets pricing model, in other words
this alpha is fully random,
then you should be a passive investor.
Just buy an index and hold it.
If you believe active managers,
that they can find alpha,
then you should consider
being an active investor.