Suppose now that instead of
just looking at one stock,
you want to think about a portfolio.
And remember that a portfolio is
defined by the various weights
that indicate how much of your funds
you've allocated to each stock.
So recall that for
an individual stock, i,
it's return on any particular day is
Bi times return on the market for
that day plus alpha for
that particular day.
So, to compute the return for the entire
portfolio, we compute this return for
each individual stock, multiply it
by the weight for that stock and
then we take the sum
across all the stocks.
And that's what we get for
the entire portfolio.
Now if you note we can
calculate beta for
the entire portfolio
simply by doing this.
Beta for the overall portfolio
is simply a weighted sum
of the individual betas for
each of the stocks.
So the capital assets pricing model
tells us that we can simplify
the expected overall return for
a portfolio by computing a beta for
that portfolio, multiplying it
by the return on the market and
then there's some alpha.
So that alpha is composed
of multiple example.
So this alpha, remember capital assets
pricing models says that all of these
are on average going to be zero, so we
don't need to bother necessarily adding
them up, we can just approximate
it by an overall portfolio alpha.
So again, this is what the CAPM tells us
we can expect on any particular day, and
again, CAPM asserts that this
alpha is random with mean 0.
The active portfolio manager will say,
okay, yes,
I agree that the beta component is
the same as CAPM at pricing model says.
But I think I can find
value in this alpha and
it needs to be broken out individually.
So the active portfolio manager
is going to have this formulation
of what they could expect in return
each day compared to the CAPM,
which is a little bit simpler.