Let's summarize now
the implications of CAPM.
Let's start first with the equation.
So the CAPM tells us that the expected
return on our portfolio is the veta
of the portfolio times the return on
the market plus alpha of the portfolio.
The first point, an important point,
is that alpha is random, and
the expected value of alpha is zero.
So that excludes alpha from our
toolbox of ways to make money.
What's left?
So the only way we can beat the market
now is by cleverly choosing beta, so
that when the market is going up,
we choose a positive beta, and
when a markets going down we choose
a lower or even negative beta.
So CAPM says the only way we can beat
the market is with high beta and
up markets and
low beta and down markets.
The only problem with that is
the efficient markets hypothesis.
We haven't covered that yet,
but it's coming soon.
But anyways,
the efficient markets hypothesis
says you can't predict the market.
So, these avenues are not
available to you, either.
So, all these things taken together
say that you can't beat the market.
If the capital assets pricing model
is true, we can't beat the market.
Now, I don't believe that, and
this whole course is about ways that
you can potentially beat the market.
So, we're going to get
to those eventually,
but we had to present
the capital assets pricing model
as a framework in which to
consider all these other things.