Now before we close, there's one
other thing I want to touch on.
It's called Arbitrage Pricing Theory.
Arbitrage Pricing Theory was
developed by Stephen Ross and
first published in 1976.
So Dr. Ross observed the CAPM as it was.
But he said look,
we have this single beta
that represents a particular
stock's relationship to the market.
Maybe really we ought
to have multiple betas.
The CAPM is really only allowing us to
consider a stock in the entire ocean.
And his idea, if you continue the sort
of analogy we've been doing in this
class, is that we ought to
consider the different islands.
In other words,
a particular stock might have exposure
to different aspects of the market.
So, the stock might have
some exposure to finance, so
we could compute the component of
return due to finance via the beta
with regard to finance and
the return for finance of that day.
So we could compute for each stock,
for each sector, and individual beta.
And so his assertion was that
by breaking out the betas
into these different factors,
we could get a more accurate forecast of
what the return's going to look like.
And of course we still
have our alpha over here.
We're not going to use APT in this
class, but since we've been going
forward with this analogy of oceans and
islands and so on, I wanted to bring
it to your attention because I
thought you might find it interesting.
Okay, that's it for
the capital assets pricing model.
I'll see you again soon.