In this lesson, we're going to take a
look at the various kinds of statistics
that we can take on time series data.
Let's start first with
global statistics.
Consider our trusty data frame DF1 with
columns for SPY, XOM, Google, and Gold.
We can take the mean
of each of these columns very
simply with a statement like this.
This statement will take
the mean of each column and
put it in the appropriate location
of a new one-dimensional or
row-wise of the array.
Now because this is a data frame,
and remember,
a data frame augments NumPy and
provides a lot more functionality.
It's sort of in the array on steroids.
Now we get lots and lots of
functions we can access in this way.
We already mentioned mean in
addition to mean we've got median,
standard deviation, sum, prod, mode.
All together there's at least 33 global
statistics you can compute in this way.
And they're always adding more.
Let me hand it over to Dave and
she's going to show you
how to do this in code.