We're going to introduce a new kind of
statistic now called rolling statistics,
and as opposed to just
taking the mean across
the whole period of time we take
sort of a snapshot over windows.
I'll show you what that
means in just a moment.
Now on that last slide,
we computed a global mean,
which would be something
about like this on this data.
A rolling mean is a little bit
different and here's how it works.
Let's suppose we're going to
take a 20 day rolling mean.
We go, starting from here,
20 days, it's right about here.
And then we take the mean
of all that data behind us.
We can draw a little box around that.
This is called the window.
In our case, it's 20 days.
So we average all these values, and
we get one mean, which is this point.
We then move the window forward
one day and we take another mean.
Here's our next mean,
which is a little bit higher.
Now if we do that everyday over
this entire year, so this is S and
P 500 over the year 2012, we get
something that looks about like this.
You can see essentially, that it's
a line that follows the day-to-day
values of whatever it is we're tracking,
but it lags a little bit.
It's sort of a smoothed and lagged line.
And this is called the rolling mean.
We can compute statistics like this,
just like the rolling mean.
We could do standard deviation.
We could do mode, median and so on.
All of those statistics I
showed you just a moment ago
can also be used as rolling statistics.
In the next mini course we are going to
spend a lot of time talking about
technical indicators, and this is
actually one of them this rolling mean,
it's called by technical
analysts a simple moving average.
And one thing they
look at is places where
the price crosses through
the rolling average.
So, in this case, the price is
moving down through the 20 day mean.
Now a hypothesis that I'm
not saying I support, but
a hypothesis that many who
conduct technical analysis,
is that this rolling mean may be a good
representation of sort of the true
underlying price of a stock, and
that significant deviations from that,
like this one here eventually
result in a return to the mean.
So if you can look for, say
significant deviations like this one,
you might find say
a buying opportunity here.
A challenge though, is to know when
is that deviation significant enough
that you should pay attention to it.