Returning to that question of
how can we know if a deviation
from the rolling mean is significant
enough to warrant a trading signal,
we need some way of measuring that.
And John Bollinger, in the 1980s,
came up with something he
calls Bollinger bands.
And whenever you mention that you
have to put a little R there,
because he has registered
Bollinger bands as a trademark.
If you don't do that,
they'll come after you.
[LAUGH] Anyhow,
how might we measure that?
What Bollinger observed
was that we ought
to take a look at the recent
volatility of the stock.
And if it's very volatile,
we might discard movements above and
below the mean.
Whereas if it's not very volatile,
a similarly sized movement maybe
we should pay attention to.
His idea then was to add a band
2 standard deviations above
and 2 standard deviations below.
Now I'm not going to make any comment
as to how effective this method is.
That's something for
us to assess in the next mini course.
But the theory anyways is that when
you see excursions up to 2 sigma or
2 standard deviations away from
the mean, you should pay attention.
And in particular,
if we drop below that and
then up back through it,
that is potentially right there
a buy signal, because the hypothesis
there is that we've gone quite far
from the simple moving average.
And we're now moving back towards it.
So if you buy there,
you should anticipate positive returns
as it climbs back through the average.
Similarly, here where you see
it punch through the top and
then go back down through,
that's potentially a sell signal.
And as you can see, in this particular
case, if we had bought here and
sold there, we would've done great.
But if you look at many, many examples
of this, it's not always so great.
So don't run off and start trading, but
just be aware that this is an example
of a technical indicator, and how you
might involve it in a trading strategy.
Dave is now going to show you
how to read in data like this,
compute a rolling mean, and chart it.
And once again, I want to repeat
that I'm not necessarily endorsing
technical analysis here, although
I think it can be very powerful.
Just introducing some of
these concepts to you.
And again, in our later mini course,
we're going to talk a lot
about these approaches.
Okay, here's to you, Dave.