It's quiz time.
Professor explained to you how
to get Bollinger Bands and
now you get to try it yourself.
Here's the data frame containing
the stock prices for SPY for year 2012.
Now computing Bollinger Bands
consists of three main steps.
First, compute rolling mean followed by
computing rolling standard deviation.
And then, finally, computing the values
for the upper and the lower bands.
We want you to implement
one function for each step.
You can call each
function in this manner.
Note that in this case,
we use a window size of 20 for
calculating rolling statistics.
But we should be able to vary this.
Finally, we plot the original prices,
rolling mean, and the Bollinger Bands.
Let me start you out with
one of the functions.
Here is how I would
implement get_rolling_mean.
Now go ahead and write code to compute
the rolling standard deviation and
calculate the upper and
the lower Bollinger Bands.
Wondering how to compute
rolling standard deviation?
Check out the trusty panels
documentation for that.
Now refer back to the previous
video if you forgot how to
calculate Bollinger Bands.