Note how we calculated the rolling mean.
The rolling standard deviation can
be computed in a very similar way.
Pandas provide a function called
rolling_std to do this job.
We simply pass in the values and
the window size.
Now, onto Bollinger bands.
Recall that upper bound is two standard
deviation above the rolling mean.
Let's type this in our code.
Here, we add 2 times the value of
the rolling standard deviation to
the rolling mean.
Though the mean and the standard
deviation values are in the form of
CD's, the mathematics still works.
It is similar to the arithmetic
operation on numpy arrays,
which is done element-wise.
Next, let's calculate
lower_band in a similar way.
Here, I subtracted 2 times the rolling
standard deviation values from
the rolling mean.
Note that will return the values for
the two bands together.
These are received back when
the function is called.
Let's see if a function computes
Bollinger bands correctly.
Looks good to me.
Observe the selling and
the buying points.
You can play with the window size and
see how the bands change.
You could also try computing
bands at different deviation
away from the rolling mean.