Now we're going to look at
something called Daily Returns.
Daily returns are one of the most
important statistics used in
financial analysis.
So let's consider first here this
time series, S&P 500 in 2012.
What daily returns are is simply
how much did the price go up or
down on a particular day?
So, for instance,
on this day it went down a little.
On the next day it went up a lot.
Daily returns are calculated easily
using a simple equation here.
So the daily return for
day t, let's say today,
is simply today's stock price divided
by yesterdays' stock price, minus one.
Let me show you an example.
Let's suppose on this particular
day the price went from $100
yesterday to $110 today.
The daily return then, for that day,
is (110/100)- 1, or
1.1- 1 = .1, which is 10%.
So that's how we
calculate daily returns.
Now one thing to remember is this is a
kind of statement you might put in a for
loop where you iterate
over individual days.
Don't do that.
Use the NumPy syntax we showed you,
where you can do this in a single
statement with no for loops.
Here's what a chart for
daily returns might look like.
Everything is scaled now
from minus 10% to plus 10%.
And what we see here is
the daily return for each day.
If it was a positive return,
of course it's positive, and
negative if it were negative.
Remember the day when we calculated
we had a positive return of 10% that
corresponds to that point right here.
And for instance, here on the next
day we had negative daily return.
That corresponds to
that point right here.
Key thing to remember here is this
is a line that sort of zigs and
zags, usually close to zero.
And if you were to, say,
take the mean of all these
values because we've had a generally
upward moving trend here,
our mean would probably be
a little bit positive, above zero.
Where looking at daily returns can
be really important and revealing
is to compare daily returns between
different stocks or different assets.
So, for example we might compare how
Exxon moves in comparison to S&P 500.
As one example,
if you take a look at this section here
you can see that when S&P 500 went up,
Exxon went down and that's revealed here
in this section of the daily returns.
We're going to spend a lot of
time in some future lessons,
looking at how these statistics,
specifically how daily returns between
different assets, can be revealing.
Dave is going to show you now in Python,
how to calculate these
daily return values.
Here's to you, Dave.