First we make a copy of the data frame,
where we can save computed values.
Dataframe.copy will help us with that.
For the next part, let's consider this.
Suppose we want daily returns for
date at index T,
then we need to divide the value at
index T by the value at index T minus 1.
And subtract 1.
We want to do that for all the dates,
starting with index 1.
Now let's code this.
Here, df[1:] picks all
the rows from 1 till the end.
And df[:-1] picks all the rows
from 0 till 1 less than the end.
This operation cannot
be done at index zero
since we do not have the price
of the stock prior to this day.
So we set the values at
the zero throw to all zeros.
Finally, we return this data frame.
You must be wondering why did
we use dot values attribute of
one of the intermediate data frames.
The reason is to access
the underlying num pi array.
This is necessary because when given two
data frames, Pandas will try to match
each row based on index when performing
element wise arithmetic operations.
So all our effort in shifting the values
by one will be lost if we do not use
.values attribute.
Okay, now let's run this.
Here is what the daily returns look like
compared to the original stock prices.
As you can see, the original prices
of SPY and XOM are quite different.
However since the daily returns
are implicitly normalized,
they show up at a comparable scale.
Each daily return value
is either positive or
negative fraction related to
the previous day's value.
This reveals that Exxon or
Exxon Mobil actually matches ups and
downs of the SPY quite closely.
There is another way to
compute daily returns.
This time,
directly using Pandas data frame.
Here is how we can do it using
Pandas data frame function, shift.
Note that we still have to replace
the values at the zero true with zeroes.
The reason for doing this is,
Pandas leaves these unknown
values as 9 by default.
Now let's check the output.
As you can see the result
is same as before.