I'm Tucker Balch, we're here with
Tammer Kamel, founder of Quandl.
We're going to dive now into details
about how the Quandl platform works.
So let's start with
sort of a big picture,
imagine I'm a hedge fund and
I'm interested in working with Quandl.
How does Quandl fit in to my work flow?
>> Right.
So in any hedge fund where quantitative
thinking is some or
part of the investment strategy,
then at the very start of that process,
is good, high-quality data.
And that's where Quandl starts and
finishes, in a sense.
We view it as our mission to get the
data that professional investors need
into their hands and
into the format that they need it in.
>> So Quandl offers a hedge
fund literally dozens of
mechanisms to pull that data.
Whether it's a low level API and they
can pull the data right into a database
that they're maintaining themselves,
or into Python or R,
or MatLab or Stata or
any analysis tool they might be using.
But we consider our job,
mission accomplished for
Quandl, if we quickly and
painlessly get the hedge fund the data
they need into the system they want.
>> Now presumably, this includes
a combination of historical data and
live data.
Are all of your feeds
historical as well as live?
Or are there some that
are special in some way?
>> Right, so all of our data is
historical for sure, and updated daily.
Live data is a little bit
in the future for us,
it's not available on
the platform as of this moment.
>> So I could imagine
a flow something like this.
Lots of people are on a daily cycle.
I think that's a majority
of what people do.
You might read historical data to inform
your model or build some sort of model.
But after market close, you wait
some period until the market data
is available and then whatever data one
might pull from Quandl, do some number
crunching overnight and put in orders
for what you might do in the next day.
Now what time does
your data available and
what mechanisms do
people use to pull it?
>> So what you described is really
a canonical use case for Quandl, right.
A fund or an analyst will take
the historical data, build and
calibrate a model, and when they're
comfortable that it's ready for
action, then they're going to
start executing on it.
So Quandl market data is updated
pretty quickly after the close,
within minutes or depending on the exact
database, we're talking about ours so.
But definitely in time to run today's
numbers through your model to get
the output and know what actions need
to be taken on the next trading day.
>> So I love to learn details about how
people build complex financial systems.
So where do your machines live?
>> So
Quandl is quite modern in that respect.
Everything lives in the Cloud.
We're customers of Amazon,
like so many others are.
At the heart of Quandl is a modern,
no SQL database.
And that's where the 15,
16 million times series,
few billion data points live there.
On top of that, we've built an API.
And then the Quandl website itself,
interestingly, is itself just
another client of the Quandl API.
If you look at our website, you will
discover it's perfectly orthodox.
It's a standard Ruby on Rails website,
built very conventionally, it's just
another client of the Quandl API.
>> Why the choice of no SQL?
>> So because of scalability, right?
We really need to be able to deliver
lots of numerical data to lots of people
very, very quickly.
The number of data points in
the Quandl database is in the order of
a few billion now, but
we expect that to be 10 or 20 or
50 billion within a year or
two, and at that point,
conventional relational databases
get kind of difficult to work with.
>> So the glue between the various
components is Ruby on Rails?
>> It is, indeed, yeah.
>> So it's no SQL and
Ruby on Rails, and that's it?
>> That is it.
Quandl is,
by software engineering standards,
pretty plain, vanilla,
simple implementation.
Where Quandl, where we sweat day-to-day
is usually in maintaining
the accuracy of 12 million data sets.
The technical infrastructure is,
not to say it's trivial, but
it's conventional best
practices software engineering.
>> Getting back to the data,
tell me a little bit about timestamping.
Let me tell you what I'm getting at.
So let's just consider
market close data.
So the price for a particular stock
essentially is stamped at 4 o'clock,
so one potential timestamp for
that data is New York time,
[LAUGH] one potential timestamp for
that data is 4PM,
but maybe I can't observe it until 4:05.
That's just one example.
But I'm curious, does that sort of time
stamping feed into what you all do?
>> Yeah,
that's actually a really good point.
I suppose what you're getting at is the
risk of creating a look-ahead bias in
your analysis, right?
>> Yeah.
You know what,
I can't claim that Quandl has any sort
of panaceas for that sort of thing.
We time stamped the data, of course.
And the meticulous, diligent analyst
should be aware of this kind of thing.
And they'll see that this database is
the 4PM closing prices, but-
>> This more likely did occur with
things like earnings reports.
>> Yeah.
With those sort of things,
we reach to the vendors and
the publishers for this, but they are
acutely aware of that, so you'll see.
Take for example our earnings data.
They're both as reported to the point
and time data and revised data.
So those kind of blatant
risks of the look-ahead bias,
those are well mitigated.
>> When you look at your various
vendors who are providing you data,
what sorts of flaws do
you see in that data and
what sorts of steps to you have
to take to mitigate those flaws?
>> It's interesting,
there's no such thing as a perfect
data set in this world, right, and
we're of course strongly motivated to
get as close to that ideal as possible.
The way we've done it is kind of simple,
but also a little bit original.
And it falls from the mechanism we've
set up, where consumers of data
have a direct relationship with
the publishers of those data.
And indeed, the publisher of the data's
livelihood depends on keeping that
consumer satisfied or happy.
And so unlike sort of many
other data platforms,
where there's a lot of opacity
between the end user and
a lot of layers too, between the end
user and the actual publisher.
In fact, you might in many cases,
not even be able to reach the publisher.
Quandl has this direct relation.
So what you find is that if and
when there's errors in the data,
our publishers are very keen
to correct it, and fast.
Because they've got 5 or 10 or
50 customers who know it's them
who are responsible for it, and
they're keen to keep these
people paying for the service.
Right?
So this is an amazing,
this is a reality that
happens in many marketplaces.
When you start removing the distance
between the end consumer and
the actual producer of the product,
you get this quality improvement.
The other thing that, of course,
affects that is good old healthy
competition on a marketplace.
We actually, right now, for some
databases, we have two or more vendors
offering competing products and nothing
drives quality control like competition.
>> Okay, great interview.
Thanks very much.
I'm sure the students out there
will find this fascinating.
Thanks for your time,
I really appreciate that.
That's the end of this discussion with
Tammer Kamel, and we'll see you online.