Hi there, I'm Tucker Balch.
I'm here with Tammer Kamel,
he's founder of Quandl.
We're here at Quantcon, which is
a conference organized by Quantopian.
So I want to talk with you now about
your experience advising hedge funds.
I guess you have some experience
actually managing money.
And students in the class are really
interested to hear about real
live strategies that succeeded or
failed or lessons learned.
So what is jump diffusion?
>> The jump diffusion
was a model to try and
capture the sixth sigma event.
And the idea here was,
it was a smart idea, and
I can't take credit for it entirely.
But the idea here was if you
mix normal distributions and
drew from them at
different probabilities.
So for example, you had a distribution
with volatility of sigma.
>> I think I know what you're talking
about, but I just want to review it,
in case folks there, so they can follow.
So you might have a distribution of
returns for one strategy or one stock.
>> Right.
>> And so you're talking about
the distributions for maybe different
strategies or different stocks and then
potentially combining them in some way.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And everybody assumes those
distributions are Gaussian, right?
So the bell curve-
>> Right.
And so, Gaussian distributions are so
delightful to work with, right?
>> [LAUGH]
>> So,
the problem is that reality doesn't
intersect with them that much, right?
But one nice thing you can do is you can
actually simulate reality a little bit
better if you use not one, but
two Gaussian distributions.
And as your random variable moves,
you draw usually from
the first normal distribution.
But then with some random probability,
you draw from a distribution with
a much higher standard deviation.
Thus simulating these rare events and
creates the fatter tails, and
is great for risk management.
It's predicted power is minimal,
because it's random so you don't.
But for risk management it really gives
you a much better sense of the fact
that- [CROSSTALK]
>> So
you might have a current portfolio and
do some sort of Monte Carlo simulation
to see how risky that portfolio is.
>> That's exactly the use case.
>> Gotcha, gotcha.
Okay, okay.
So in one of your earlier careers
[LAUGH], you advised hedge funds.
What sorts of strategies did
your company generate and
advise the hedge funds on?
>> So I graduated from an engineering
program at the university in
the mid 90s.
And I always call this sort of the
golden age of quantitative financing.
It was an era when Wall Street was
plucking young vulnerable engineers
like myself,
>> [LAUGH]
>> And having us mathematically
model markets.
And back then there was all
kinds of really fat opportunity.
The first thing we used to do was-
>> Anybody with a computer could make
money, right?
[LAUGH]
>> Well if you could do a bit of math
you really could, right.
There was this thing, we made a lot
of money on was yield per arbitrage.
>> If you did just a [CROSSTALK]
model the swap curve, for
example, with a two or
three factor model.
And you would discover, a,
that at any given time,
some deviation between a sensible
looking yield curve and
what was-
>> So
a particular asset would be currently
priced in a such a way to be contrary to
what the yield curve would predict?
>> What it would come down to is it
would be mis-priced relative to its
peers on that yield curve, right?
And backtesting would tell you,
would confirm that time and again,
that anomaly would revert back
to something more normal, right?
So you could make a lot of money by
taking these reasonably sophisticated
yield curve positions.
Where you were long at two points of
the curve, and short at two other
points of the curve, and you get these
funky butterfly kind of trades, right?
But they'd be sort of neutral
to the level of the curve, and
even neutral to the slope of the curve,
but there's these third and
fourth factors that would
be in revert all the time.
>> So, to take a short
position in a fixed income,
you would have to be
a credit swap of some sort?
Or how would you do that?
>> Many ways you can do that.
Credit swap certainly does it.
There was no such thing as a credit
swap when we were doing this.
You could short a government bond,
borrow it and
sell it in the repo market?
>> I just think of with the way you
can trade today electronically,
you never really think about
the borrowing and the reselling.
>> Right we used to
worry about that stuff.
Yeah repo rates, and all of that.
But yeah, that's been extracted
away to some extent, right?
But yeah, that's how we used to do it.
>> But, so you talked about
looking at yield curves.
Did you all do anything in equities?
Or was it just primarily
the fixed income?
>> We did, also in the 90s, stat arb and
even simple pair trades were very
effective trading strategies, right?
There was a lot more
inter-stock volatility.
A lot less correlation between the
stocks, at least until the late 90s and
the crash.
And you could even do more sophisticated
stuff like the stat arp stuff or
eigenvalue PCA analysis
on stock markets and
do sort of payer trading
strategies on these.
>> So a lot of that stuff
doesn't work anymore.
>> No it doesn't.
>> [LAUGH]
>> That's why I started a data company.
>> I see, okay.
Anyways, I wanted to ask
to what do you attribute
the evaporation of alpha and
these kinds of approaches?
>> I think there's a lot of
interesting things going on, right?
There's no question that
the number of participants
executing similar
strategies is a factor.
Volatility is low these days, right?
And these strategies thrive in high
volatility environments, right?
Like the 90s was a much higher
volatility environment,
even in a bull market.
Another big advantage we had in the 90s
was the phenomenon of the day trader,
which was for lack of a better term,
incompetent trading.
>> Right.
>> Right, which would create all kinds
of wacky, if the day traders woke up on
a Tuesday morning and they were
all in love with Ebay for example.
Then everybody just went and
bought that, and
it would create a mispricing in Ebay,
right?
But what you don't have irrational
actors in the marketplace,
it makes these relative value
pair trades are harder to adapt.
>> And I guess at that time maybe the
day traders were a higher percentage of
the volume, right?
>> It was definitely a large
fraction of the volume, or
a meaningful faction of the volume.
>> Taking food from children's mouths.
[LAUGH]
>> So if someone were,
some young whipper snapper
wants to go out and
start creating some kind
of systematic strategy,
is there any alpha left out there?
Or where should somebody
like that start?
>> Oh, I'm sure there's all
kinds of alpha to be had.
It's just you have to, don't look
in the same old places because
everybody already has been there and
there's only a bit.
I think there is all kinds
of opportunity if you find
new information sources.
You hear great stories about
little creative ideas where
you pay someone sitting in China to
count trucks coming out of a factory.
>> Right, right.
>> Right, you've heard this one.
And then you get a sense of how
production is going for that company.
Very simple little
information advantage.
>> Right.
Mechanical Turk like sorts of things.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's all kinds of things
you can do with that.
>> So I think that's fascinating.
The one thing I would say to sort
of reinforce the kind of thing
that Quandl can offer is we often
find that the combination of
different data sources adds value.
So as an example, maybe over simplified.
Back in the 90s, a strategy,
say based on Bollinger Bands,
might have worked when you hit
the top that could be a cell signal.
Nowadays, that just by itself,
it doesn't work.
[LAUGH] But, a combination of multiple
technical indicators plus some
fundamental data, putting all those
together instead of just a simple,
single factor model can work.
>> Yeah, I know, I think so.
I still have,
there's three rules of thumb for
building quantitative
strategies these days.
I think one should look for
theoretically sound ideas.
So don't bet on black box,
neural net, kind of things,
because they always fall down, right?
But if something makes theoretical sense
in an economics or financial sense,
it's a good chance
you're onto something.
>> So it's a good intuitive
story to start with.
>> Exactly,
it actually should make sense on
a whiteboard to start with, right?
Grounded in some of the fundamental
principals that we know govern
financial markets in economics right?
Number two is empirically tested, right?
So build something that's
theoretically sound and
then show yourself empirically,
with data, that this thing worked.
And then the final thing
is be scared of complexity.
If it doesn't stay simple its a warning
sign your probably over fitting and
getting yourself into a trap.
But if you devise a strategy
that ticks these three boxes,
that it's sort of theoretically sound,
empirically testable, and still simple,
you're probably on the right track.
>> Yeah.
[LAUGH] That's great.
I'm in total agreement with you.
So, one last question.
So we've talked about things to do or
how to attack it.
What should people run from,
[LAUGH] what should they be scared of?
>> Look I think the single biggest trap,
and I've fallen into this thing myself,
right, is if you find yourself
calibrating the same model
on the same data usually,
and you calibrate it.
Oh, it doesn't quite work.
And then you turn a few knobs and
it doesn't quite work.
And then the eighth time
you finally turn the knobs
just right and it's working?
Odds are you've just curve fitted,
right?.
Don't fall into that trap of
endlessly iterating on the same data.
Because you're in for
unpleasant surprises once you get into,
out of sample data.
>> Great.
Yeah.
[LAUGH] You're totally going to
reinforce the things I say in the class,
so that's awesome, but
they don't believe it when
they hear it just from me.
>> Trust me.
I've lost a lot of my [LAUGH]
>> Cool.
Well that's it.
Fantastic, great interview.
Thanks so much for your time Tammer.
>> The pleasure was mine Tucker,
thank you.
>> And hope you all enjoyed it and
I'll see you online.
So long.