Let's start by looking at a few
characteristics of technical analysis.
First, what is it?
One of the most important things to
remember about technical analysis
is that it looks only at price and
volume.
That's as opposed to fundamental
analysis that looks at fundamental
factors, like earnings, dividends,
cash flow, book value, and so on.
Technical analysis is price and
volume only.
We look back at historical price and
volume to compute statistics
on this time series, and
these statistics are called indicators.
Indicators are heuristics that may
hint at a buy or sell opportunity.
Now there is significant criticism
of the technical approach.
Folks consider that it's not
an appropriate method for
investing, because it's not considering
the value of the companies.
Instead, maybe you could think about
it as a trading approach as opposed to
an investing approach.
Still there are reasons to believe that
technical analysis might have value and
that it might work.
First of all,
there is indeed information in price and
information in price change.
It reflects sentiments of buyers and
sellers, and especially if we see that
the price for a particular stock
is moving in a different direction
than the overall market, that might be
a hint that there's something going on.
Additionally, we know that in other
domains of artificial intelligence,
heuristics can work, and
they work frequently.
So even though it's controversial,
there are reasons to believe
technical analysis can work.