So over the last few years I've been
using technical analysis a lot.
I've also been using
fundamental analysis.
And people often ask me well, you know,
when is one valuable versus the other.
Let's look first at technical
analysis and where it's effective.
Here's some rules of
thumb that I've built for
myself over the last few years.
First is individual indicators,
by themselves, are weakly predictive.
Now back in the 80's and
90s when some of these were creative,
I believe they had stronger value.
But since that time, more and more
people have been trading according to
them, and essentially the more people
who are following a particular approach,
the less value is realized
by any person by themselves.
So individual indicators are weak.
However, combining multiple
indicators adds value.
I see over and over again that
combinations of three to five different
indicators, in a machine learning
context, provide a much stronger
predictive system than just
an individual indicator.
Another useful approach is to look for
contrasts.
In other words, look for one stock that
has a strongly different indicator
than another stock, or a stock
that is contrasting to the market.
In other words, if all stocks are
behaving in the same way as the market,
there's no reason to pick any
one stock over another, but
if you see certain stocks
are behaving differently
than the market then they
are worth a further look.
Finally, technical analysis generally
works better over shorter time
periods than longer time periods.