To understand the value of technical
analysis versus fundamental,
it's valuable to consider
the trading horizon.
In other words when you buy a stock and
sell it, what's the time period
between those two activities.
So, it can be milliseconds,
maybe even smaller time periods.
It can be days or it can be years.
So, for instance, Warren Buffett
often buys and holds stocks for
years, high frequency traders are
trading on the order of milliseconds.
So to illustrate what I mean,
consider Fundamental factors.
If we are trading over a time period
of milliseconds How much do fundamental
factors contribute to the change in
price over those short periods of time?
When we're trading machines
on the stock exchange,
what really matters is what's
happening there on the stock exchange.
For instance, the order book or
momentum and so on.
So at these short time periods,
Fundamental factors
really have low value.
Now consider all the way out to years,
we know from, for
instance, Warren Buffet's success,
that fundamental
factors over long periods of
time may have significant value.
What about days?
Well, maybe over a period of days
Fundamental factors do have value.
So, imagine that we sort
of chart it like this.
Over long periods of time, fundamental
factors provide a lot of value.
Consider the same sort of chart now,
but for technical factors.
Let's start out over here,
over many years.
Think about if we make
a technical analysis of a stock,
what it's 20 day momentum is which
we'll talk about in a moment.
How much is that really going to affect
the price of a stock years later.
Very little.
So over long terms technical
analysis is not so valuable.
Think back now to very very
short periods of time.
This is where technical
analysis can shine, and
it potentially has high value
over very short periods of time.
So we have a chart that looks a lot like
the fundamental chart, but it's swapped.
Let's consider a couple other factors.
I won't draw the charts like these,
but just think about these.
So consider for instance,
decision complexity.
How complex is the decision to buy or
sell a stock if you're
going to hold it for years.
Becomes more complex this way.
How about decision speed?
How fast do the decisions
have to be made?
Well, certainly, we have to be
able to make the decisions really,
really fast if we're trading
at the millisecond level.
And of course we can take
a long time to make a decision
if we're going to buy and
hold for years.
So as you look across this spectrum,
consider where is the best region for
humans to operate and where is the best
region for computers to operate?
Well, because at this
very high frequency
the complexity of decisions is simple.
Computers can make this decisions very,
very fast and that also happens to
be where technical analysis has value
which is the domain of the computer.
So computers excel in
this region of the chart.
Over here where we can take a long
time ti make a decision and
the decisions are complex.
This is the best region for
human investors.
So, if you look at different types of
hedge funds the high frequency trading
computer driven hedge funds
are operating over here.
The insight driven, human based
hedge funds are operating over here.
And then there's this region in
the middle where we often see humans and
computers working together.