There are hundreds of technical
indicators out there.
We're going to take a look at
just three because, of course,
our time is limited but I will point you
to resources online where you can learn
about other indicators.
Theres three are some of the most common
and most popular that people use.
The three we will look at are momentum,
simple moving average, and
Bollinger Bands.
Let's take a look first at momentum.
Momentum is really one of
the simplest indicators, and
it's just over some number of days
how much has the price changed.
So for instance,
if we look at this point to this point,
we've got positive momentum.
Or if we were to look from here to here,
we've got negative momentum.
The steepness of that line is
the strength of the momentum,
either positive or negative.
Now, in terms of using this in a trading
strategy, there are many folks who look
at the momentum for a stock, the recent
momentum, and if it's positive they buy,
because they anticipate that
the momentum is going to continue.
Now, I'm not necessarily
recommending that to you.
I'm just telling you
how some people use it.
Now I'm going to show
you in a later slide,
how we can use momentum as
part of a combined strategy.
Now, you can see here how we
can look at momentum visually.
But for
machine learning, which of course we're
going to get to in the next mini course,
we actually need to convert these to
numbers that we can use quantitatively.
And, of course, this course is
about quantitative analysis.
So there's always, for
technical analysis, a graphical or
visual presentation, but we need to also
consider the quantitative presentation.
So, when we talk about momentum, we talk
about how many days of momentum that is.
So, that might be n days,
where we use n right there.
So, n might be a number like 5 or
10 and so on.
Here's the pseudo code for how we
compute momentum on a particular day.
So let's suppose this
is day t right here.
We just take the price
as of that day and
we divide it by the price in
days earlier and subtract 1.
So this will give us a number, say 0.1,
if the price has gone up 10% or
-0.1, if it's gone down 10%.
So we usually see numbers in
the range of, say, about -0.5 for
a big, significant,
50% drop, to about +0.5.
So on any particular day,
this is how we would calculate the value
of this technical indicator momentum.