Our next indicator is simple
moving average or SMA.
And again, it's indexed by n, which
is how many days are we looking back.
So if we want to calculate the value of
the simple moving average for this day,
we look back over n days, and
this is called an n-day window.
So the SMA for
today is simply the average of
the values over this look back period.
So it would be a value
about right there.
And if we carry it forward,
it'll look like this.
So, the SMA looks
essentially like a smoothed
value of the price chart
as it moves around.
And an important thing to note
is it sort of lags the movement.
So as we started down here,
it slowly started coming down,
and when we started up here,
it lagged that movement upwards.
There are at least two different
ways that technicians use
simple moving average as
parts of trading strategies.
The first is they look for
places where the current price crosses
through the simple moving average.
Those tend to be important events,
especially if the average is over many,
many days.
If you combine that with momentum,
in other words,
the price has strong momentum, and
it's crossing through that simple
moving average, that can be a signal.
This particular crossing,
where the price goes through the simple
moving average, doesn't really
illustrate strong momentum
because it just started going up.
However, when you do see strong momentum
crossing those lines, then again,
that can be a trading signal.
Another way that technicians use simple
moving average is as a proxy for
underlying value.
In other words, if you look back
over a certain period of time and
take that average price, that might
represent the true value of the company.
And if we see a large excursion from
that price, we should, for instance,
here and here, we should expect that
the price is eventually going to
come back down to that average.
And so it's an arbitrage opportunity,
sort of like we saw with
fundamental analysis.
And again, for example, there's a large
excursion downward here, so this might
represent a buy opportunity, and these
two might represent sell opportunities.
Because there was a strong
diversion from that moving average.
Now we talked about earlier how
every technical indicator has
a visual presentation like
I'm showing you here, but
we also need a way to quantify it,
to turn it into a number.
The way we do that is to compare
the current price with the current
simple moving average,
and construct a ratio.
So, in this case, we would look for
a negative value.
And in these cases,
we'd want to see positive values.
So, if we were to calculate, say, the
value of the simple moving average on
this day, we take the price for
that day, and
we compute the mean for
the last n-days, which is here.
And remember, this is over
a look back window of n-days.
Divide that into the price and
subtract one.
So, if, for instance, the price is
10% above the simple moving average,
we'd end up getting a positive 0.1.
If it were 10% below,
we'd get a negative 0.1.
So similar to the momentum, we
typically see values here ranging from,
at most, minus 50% to plus 50%.