Let's suppose you liked what I told
you about simple moving average, and
you're looking at the historical
price of this stock.
And you're trying to decide,
okay, how much of an excursion
from the simple moving average should
I use as a signal for a buy or sell?
So let's add our simple
moving average line here.
Now you might say, okay, I think I
see an excursion of say 1% like this,
that that's a meaningful excursion and
I should trade based on that.
So let's carry forward and now you're
getting this huge excursions all
the time and you'd be chasing
it trying to trade all the time.
So clearly a fixed number is
probably not the best way to go.
If you look at this chart,
you'll see that we've got a region
of low volatility over here.
And high volatility over here.
So John Bollinger observed that for
low volatility stocks or stocks that are
currently experiencing low volatility,
you probably want to use
a smaller number for that trigger.
And when we see high volatility, you
probably want to use a larger number.
Well, how can we accomplish that, well,
we can use the standard deviation.
So what Bollinger suggested was, okay,
let's take this simple moving average,
but let's add a band above and
below two standard deviations.
And that's our measure for
how strong of a deviation we want to
see before we respond to it.
So for instance in this region,
this smaller excursion goes outside that
band, so we should take a look at it.
But over here, it takes a much larger
excursion to get our attention.
How might we use Bollinger Bands now for
trading signals?
Here's a method that I've
seen that is effective.
So here's a rule of thumb for using
Bollinger Bands that might be effective.
You look for
times where the price's outside,
one of these Bollinger Bands and
when it crosses to the inside.
So for instance, here, we're outside and
we cross to the inside.
So this would be a cell signal.
We've got a large excursion
from the simple moving average.
And we're expecting that it will
retreat back to the average.
And it's demonstrated that it's
retreating because it's gone from
outside the band back
towards the moving average.
Conversely, here we're moving
from below the lower band.
Back towards the simple moving average.
And that would be a buy signal.
So, recapping.
The way that people use
Bollinger Bands is they look for
the price to go outside the bands.
And then look for
it to retreat back through the band.
And that's verification that
it is moving back toward
the simple moving average.
Here's how to calculate the Bollinger
Band on a particular day t.
So here's the price on that particular
day t, we subtract the value of
the simple moving average, so
we are comparing these two values, and
then divide by 2 times
the standard deviation.
So the value up here is going to
be something greater than 1.0
because if it's exactly at this band,
it's exactly 2 standard deviations away,
so it would be a value
of 1 right at the band.
It's greater than 1 here.
Similarly, down here, we would
have a value less than negative 1.
Because the price excursion is more
than 2 standard deviations below.
So we typically expect to see values for
this Bollinger Band calculation
to be between negative 1, and 1.
In other words,
most of the time the stock is
going to be between those bands.
But occasionally, we'll see excursions
above and below those values.