Let's take a look at this first one.
So we went from outside the upper
band and crossed down inside it.
That is a sell signal because we've gone
very far from the moving average, and
we've validated now that we're moving
back towards the moving average so
that's a sell.
Here, we've gone from inside to outside,
and that is never a signal.
It does indicate, of course,
a significant excursion from the moving
average, but we're looking for
the validation that it comes back
inside, so this is not a signal at all.
Here however we've come back
through that bottom band, and
that is a buy signal.
Finally for this last one, number four,
we've gone outside the lower band and
we've transitioned up inside it,
that is a buy signal.
So that's Bollinger bands and
how you might use them.