Before we leave technical analysis
I want to bring up one more point
called normalization.
So, take a look at these different
technical indicators we created here,
simple moving average,
momentum, and Bollinger bands.
They have different ranges that they
typically operate over, so, like I said
we would expect to see values of -.5
to +.5 For simple moving average.
For momentum, similar kind of range.
Bollinger Band typically
inhabits -1.0 to 1.0.
If we were to plug these values into
some sort of machine learner we
would have a little bit of a problem.
And what would happen,
we'll have to go into the details later.
But the Bollinger Band factor would tend
to overwhelm these other factors and
become the most important one.
It might get even worse if we included
fundamental factor like PE ratio
that can range from 1
all the way up to 300.
The solution is something
called normalization.
And what normalization does it
takes each of these factors and
essentially compresses them or
stretches them so
that they vary on average from -1 to +1.
Normalization is simple,
you take your original values for
a particular factor subtract
the mean from all of them,
then divide by the standard
deviation of all of them.
This will give you a normed result that,
on average,
is going to vary between -1 and
1, and it'll have a mean of 0.
So remember this trick for
later when we get to machine learning,
or if you're working with technical
indicators yourself, you may want to
apply this normalization approach
to the numbers you're working with.