Let's wrap up technical analysis now.
So to review, technical indicators
are really heuristics that represent
someone's interpretation or
hunch of how a statistical approach to
previous prices and volume might
suggest future price movement.
The particular examples that I've
provided here are my approach.
So if you go look up, for instance,
on John Bollinger's website how to use
Bollinger Bands, you might discover
his approach is slightly different.
I showed you specifically how I have
found them to be useful in the past.
Finally, lots of times when people get
exposed to technical analysis they get
really excited and
they want to run off and start trading.
Well, hold your horses,
there's a lot more to learn.
So stick with it, and
we'll see you in the next lesson.