To figure out which of
these scenarios is best,
we need to consider reward and risk.
Let's start here first with reward.
So when we talk about
reward in this situation,
we're talking about our expected return.
So in the single bet case,
we bet 1000 chips at once.
Our expected return is the chance that
we'll win the bet times the return
we get plus the chance that we would
lose the bet times what we would lose.
So, the chance that we're
going to win is 0.51.
Remember, it's a biased coin.
And we have the opportunity
to win 1000 tokens or $1000.
The chance that we'll lose is 0.49 or
49%.
And if we lose, we would lose a $1,000.
So if you multiply this all out and
add it up, you end up seeing
that our expected return is $20.
I'd like for you now to figure
out what's our expected return or
what's the reward in the multibet case
where we bet 1000 individual
chips on 1000 different tables.
And all those coins are flipped at once.
All biased coins with a 51%
chance of winning for us.
What's our expected return in that case?