So, we make a bunch of individual bets,
each one has the same chances as this
one up here, except each one of those
individual bets only provides
a loss of $1 or a gain of $1.
So, each of our individual bets has
this 0.51 chance of winning $1,
and 0.49 chance of losing $1.
And we just have a thousand of those.
So if you work out the numbers it turns
out that this works out to be 0.02,
and we multiply it by a thousand and
we get $20.
So what's remarkable, or
at least interesting, is that for
both of these ways of betting,
our expected return is exactly the same.
So the reward side of this determining
which is better, is showing us
that it's the same, so why should I say
that this multibet approach is better?
Well, it turns out that that's all about
the risk, so let's look at the risk now.