Let's get back to that original
question that motivated some of this,
which is how can we relate the
performance of Renaissance technologies?
Or Jim Simons versus Warren Buffet?
And the quiz here is for
you to use the fundamental law to
see if you can relate the two.
Okay, so for this problem,
assume that both Simons and
Buffet have the same information ratio.
I'm making that up,
I don't know for sure that they do.
But this is just a simplification for
this problem.
Assume that Simons' algorithms are only
one 1000th as smart as Buffet.
So that's another way of
saying that their information
coefficient is one 1000th
the value of Buffet.
Also assume that Buffet
trades 120 times per year.
Given that, how many trades
must Simons execute in order
to maintain the information ratio
at the same level as Buffet?