The answer is 120 million,
so if Buffet trades only 120
times per year,
Simons has to trade 120 million times.
So here's how I arrived at that.
We know that their information
ratios are the same, so
we just set the equation
equal to each other.
One for Simons and one for Buffet.
So the information coefficient for
Buffet, times square to 120.
This is Buffet's information ratio.
Now this is Simon's information ratio.
It's his information coefficient
times the square root of x,
which is what we're trying to find.
Now first thing we can do is replace
ICS with what we know is that
it's one-one thousandth of Buffet's.
Now we can multiply both sides by 1,000.
And divide both sides by Buffet's IC.
And we get this.
And now we just square both sides and
we're left with x or 120 million.
Okay, that's it for the fundamental
law of active portfolio management.
I'll see you again soon, thanks.