There's a number of places
information can come from.
Let's step through a few of these sorted
from most public to least public.
But even this is certainly
not an exhaustive list.
There's many other places
we can get information.
But let's step through them.
Price volume, this is public.
It's rapid, it's quick,
everybody can see it.
This is the basis of technical analysis.
Fundamental data.
This is reported quarterly and
everybody can see it as well.
It's public, but it points more to the
root of the value of the company than
just the price volume.
Exogenous data, that's a fancy name for
a simple concept.
It's just information about
the world that effects the company.
As an example, if we were looking at
an airline stock, an exogenous piece
of data that would effect the price of
the airline stock is the price of oil.
If price of oil goes down,
usually the price of the airline stock
goes up because energy is
the number one cost for airlines.
A very important and
secretive type of information
relates to company insiders.
So, let's suppose you're a CEO, and
you know that this drug that you've
invented is about to be improved.
You might go buy shares of your
stock because you think the price of
your stock is going to go up because
that drug is going to be approved.
Now, depending on the circumstance
it may or may not be legal, but this
reflects information that you have that
people outside the company do not have.
And so this insider information
is probably the least accessible
of all these types, of course, and of
most other types of information as well.
Now, each of these types of information
has a relationship to
the efficient markets hypothesis.
In particular there's three forms of
And these types of information
relate to each of these three forms.
We'll get in to that in just a second.