There are three versions of the official
markets hypothesis that go from weak
to strong and we'll take a look
at them each one at a time.
The weak form of the EMH
says that future prices cannot be
predicted by analyzing previous prices.
The idea here is that the current price.
Reflects all information we might know.
So just by looking at these historical
prices you can't predict what
is going to happen next.
Notice, however,that this does
leave room potentially for
fundamental analysis.
The semi-strong version of the EMH
suggests that prices adjust immediately
to new public information.
So, for instance, when companies
have their quarterly reports, that
contain fundamental information, prices
react immediately to that information.
So, if semi-strong is correct,
that would seem to prohibit
even fundamental analysis.
There's one possibility left though.
One way that we might make money and
that is based on insider information.
Well, the strong version of the EMH
says we can't even make money on insider
information.
Prices reflect all information,
public and private.
So even if there's some secret
information within the company
that points to a higher price later.
The price will go up in
the face of that knowledge.
So, if the strong version of the EMH
is true, it is essentially impossible
to make money by holding a portfolio,
other than the market portfolio.
So let's recap each one
of these real quick.
The weak form says that
you can't predict future prices
by looking at historical prices.
It is silent on things
like fundamentals or
insider information,
it's just about price.
You can't profit by looking
at historical price.
Semi-strong says that public information
such as quarterly reports cause
the price to adjust quickly.
The price adjusts rapidly to
this new public information.
So semi-strong essentially says that
even fundamental analysis won't work.
Finally, the strong version says
that even insider information
can't be leveraged to
profit in the market.