Is the efficient markets
hypothesis correct?
Well, if it is,
then a lot of what we're trying to
do in this course is not possible.
Namely, we can't beat the market
using any of these strategies
we might be looking at.
Now, I think there is evidence that
certain versions of
the hypothesis are not correct.
And there are a number of very
successful hedge funds out there
that would seem to indicate that
you can make money in the market
by investing in things other
than just the market portfolio.
I would say the strong version
of the efficient markets
hypothesis is the least solid.
In other words,
the strong version says that you can't
even profit from insider information.
The reason that I think that
one is not true is because
we have seen people make money
from insider information.
Some of them have gone to jail,
but clearly,
it's a method that can provide profit,
even though it might be illegal.
This is an interesting
data set that seems to
refute the semi-strong version of the
efficient markets hypothesis as well.
It's a little bit complex, so
I'll step through it carefully.
So, let's look at the blue dots.
Each dot here represents the P/E ratio
on a particular date, so, for instance,
this stock had a P/E ratio of 20,
that's price to earnings.
That's the horizontal
component of its location.
The vertical location is
how much money did it make in
terms of price over 20 years.
So for instance, this stock had
a price/earnings ratio of 20.
And it made about 4% annualized returns.
As we go down this way,
the P/E ratio is lower.
So lower numbers for
P/E ratio are better.
If you think about it,
price divided by earnings,
if it's a lower price and has higher
earnings, you'll get a lower number.
So, presumably, lower values this way
indicate higher value for a stock.
And each group of colors represents
different decade when
the analysis was done.
So, for instance, this dark blue
was an analysis based on what
the P/E ratios of stocks
were in 1890 to 1910 and
all the way up to the red,
which was 1970 through 1985.
Now for all of these decades,
we saw that at the beginning of
the corresponding time period,
low P/E ratios corresponded
with higher returns.
So this shows that price/earnings
ratios are very predictive across many,
many decades of future returns, and
that tends to refute
the semi-strong version of the EMH.
Okay, that's it for
the efficient markets hypothesis.
I will see you again soon, bye, bye.